告诉你一件事  南基督教领协已指示共产党联系人
HOOVER:  Let me teII you something.  The SCLC has direct Communist ties.
连伟人都会腐败，对吧？
Even great men can be corrupted,  can't they?
共产主义不是政党，是疾病
Communism is not a poIiticaI party.  It is a disease.
会腐化心灵，把最和善的人化为…
It corrupts the souI,  turning even the gentIest of men...
堕落邪恶的暴君
...into vicious, eviI tyrants.
社会弥漫着不重法治的风气
What we are seeing is a pervasive  contempt for Iaw and order.
犯罪率暴增
Crime rates are soaring.
政府机关受到公开的蔑视
There's widespread,  open defiance of our authority...
记住我的话，如果不予以制止
...and, mark my words,  if this goes unchecked...
片名：强 艾德格
会使美国再度陷入无政府的深渊
...it wiII once again pIunge our nation  into the depths of anarchy.
厄文先生，一切皆由和平开始吧？
It aII starts out peacefuIIy,  doesn't it, Mr. Irwin?
你会因未能避免爆炸和暴力  而内疚一辈子
You have to Iive with the fact...  ...that you couId've heIped prevent  the bombings and the vioIence.
我更感兴趣的是你和联邦调查局
I'm more interested in what this says  about your FBI.
我长久拼命努力，不能坐视不管…
I have worked too Iong and hard  to just sit back...
坏人又出风头，对吧？
...and watch the bad guys capture  the spotIight again, haven't I?
你知道恶名昭彰的吊诡
The funny thing about notoriety...
尤其是渴望被崇拜  为成名而出名的恶名？
...especiaIIy the kind that needs adoration,  fame for fame's sake...
不制止的话必然导致恶行
...if unchecked,  it inevitabIy Ieads to viIIainy.
我建议你看清这场争执
I suggest you Iook at what this  squabbIe is reaIIy about...
免得毁掉你的最爱  你我皆知，就是调查局的名声
...before you destroy the reputation  of the thing we both know you Iove most.
（金恩博士反驳胡佛指控）
公关部犯罪纪录组的作家来了
HELEN [OVER INTERCOM]:  Sir, the writer's here from Crime Records...  ...the PR Department.
在我的会客室替他准备打字机
Set him up with a typewriter  in my outer office.
甘帝小姐，该是时候  让后代了解我一生的故事了
Miss Gandy, it's time this generation  Iearn my side of the story.
- 马上好  - 谢谢你
HELEN: Right away.  - Thank you.
1919年，史密斯探员  我在司法部的第一位老板
HOOVER:  In 1919, Agent Smith...  ...my first boss here  at the Department of Justice...
是司法部长米契帕玛
... was Attorney GeneraI  A. MitcheII PaImer.
他是教友派信徒
He was a Quaker.
他不信仰战争  但他了解实力和果决的必要性
He didn't beIieve in war, but he understood  the necessity of strength and resoIve.
人们相信历史学家的说法
BeIieve what you wiII from historians...
多数人从现代观点书写，而罔顾历史
...most write from a present perspective,  forgetting context.
但米契帕玛是一名英雄
MitcheII PaImer was a hero.
你没事吧？
PALMER: Are you aII right?  ROBERTA: Unh.
- 你没事吧？  - 没事，没事
PALMER: Are you aII right?  ROBERTA: Yes. I think. Yes.
没事的，过来
PALMER:  It's aII right. Come here.
- 别怕，别怕  - 没事了
- It's aII right, it's aII right.  ROBERTA: No, it's okay.
你还好吧？没事了
Are you okay? It's okay.
还好吗？
Are you okay?
帕玛对抗激进分子，跟我一样
HOOVER: you see,  PaImer fought the radicaIs, just as I have.
也跟我一样，他成为目标  他不是唯一受害者
And just as I have, he was targeted.  He wasn't aIone.
那一晚全国有八起爆炸案  都在晚上11点
Across the country that night,  eight bombs expIoded, aII at 1 1 p.m.
两位美国参议员
Two United States senators...
四位内阁成员  一位最高法院法官
...four cabinet members,  a Supreme Court justice...
约翰洛克斐勒、JP摩根
...John D. RockefeIIer, J.P. Morgan...
全都成为布尔什维克共产党的目标
...aII of them targeted  by BoIshevik Communists.
对，炸掉整栋楼
MAN:  Yeah, it shook the whoIe thing.
很显然激进分子的炸弹爆太快
HOOVER: It was cIear to me  the radicaI's bomb went off too soon...
街上只留下炸弹客的血迹
...Ieaving onIy his bIood in the street.
但调查员用水冲掉这一片混乱  而不是收集证据
But the inspectors used buckets to  cIean up the mess instead of coIIecting it.
他们丢弃他的枪而不是保存指纹
They discarded his gun  instead of preserving its prints.
不过这并不是警方的错
But you see,  this wasn't cIumsy poIice work.
在那些时代，这是正常程序
In those times, it was normaI procedure.
这可能是美国的末日，德怀特
This may be the end of days  for this country, Dwight.
那是1919年  之前没人尊重刑事科学
HOOVER: It was 1919, before anyone  respected criminaI science...
之前没有联邦权力和联邦调查局
...before federaI powers, before the FBI.
那天晚上我大开眼界，就在那晚
It was that night my eyes were opened.  That very night.
部长，他是邻居吗？
Is he a neighbor, sir?
不，他是我办公室的员工
No. He works in my office.
一定要有杀戮  我们屠杀是出于必要
HOOVER: ''There wiII have to be murder.  We wiII kiII because it is necessary.
我们会展开破坏  使世界免于美国的暴政机构
We wiII destroy to rid the worId  of your tyrannicaI institutions.''
那晚您去司法部长帕玛的家？
SMITH: you were at Attorney GeneraI  PaImer's home that night?
这就留给读者去想像
HOOVER: WeII, Iet's Ieave that  to the reader's imagination.
让主角保有一点神秘感很重要
You see, it's important we give  our protagonist a bit of mystery.
我会暗示有名青年符合您的样貌
SMITH: I couId aIIude to a young man  who matches your description.
最好虚实莫辨
The best of both worIds.
你在哪里取得法律学位的？
Where did you get your Iaw degree?
乔治华盛顿，我在当地长大
George Washington. I grew up here.
我住附近方便照顾我妈
I had a mom to take care of,  so I stayed cIose.
我也在那里拿到英文学位
I received an EngIish degree there aIso.
那我不必告诉你  不为人知的小事
Then I don't need to teII you that  what determines a man's Iegacy...
决定一个人的风范
...is often what isn't seen.
此刻最关键的是…
What's criticaI at this moment is...
我们重新阐明恶棍和英雄的差异
...that we re- cIarify the difference  between viIIain and hero.
你觉得跟现今有何不同？
How do you think that compares  with today?
我不确定，我想多听您说
I'm not sure, sir. I'd Iike to hear more.
我可以明天再来
I couId come back tomorrow.
好  但稿子留下
Fine. But the pages stay here.
是，长官
Of course, sir.
史密斯探员
Agent Smith.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
在走廊可别大声讲话
Never a good idea to taIk too Ioud.
早安，约翰
Good morning, John.
帕玛先生要你参加今天的紧急会议
Mr. PaImer has asked that you attend  the emergency meeting today.
葛莱德威小姐，请记得
Miss GIadweII, pIease remember...
称我胡佛先生
...it's Mr. Hoover.
两点开会
Two o'cIock.
这次别太早到，跟迟到一样失礼
Don't be too earIy this time.  It's as rude as being tardy.
秘书组的这位漂亮新人是谁呢？
And who is this IoveIy addition  to the secretariaI pooI?
海伦，自我介绍
HeIen, introduce yourseIf.
幸会了，胡佛先生  我是海伦甘帝
PIeased to meet you, Mr. Hoover.  I'm HeIen Gandy.
幸会，甘帝小姐，欢迎来到司法部
PIeased to meet you.  WeIcome to the Department of Justice.
请你告知帕玛先生我会参加
You can notify Mr. PaImer  that I wiII attend.
没问题
Of course.
他是万人迷，别当一回事
GLADWELL: He's aIways a charmer.  I wouIdn't take anything very seriousIy.
杰瑞米，我需要你帮忙
MAN:  Jeremy, I need your heIp.
我需要帮忙
I need, uh- -  Uh, heIp.
我需要你帮忙
I need your heIp.
晚安，妈
Good evening, Mother.
艾德格
Edgar.
玛西太太今早有个聚会
Madame Marcia heId court this morning.
她预言我会买件洋装
Her premonition: I shouId buy a dress.
还说你爸很快会死
She says your father wiII die soon.
等他死后  你会崛起成为全国最有权势的人
And when he does, you wiII rise to be  the most powerfuI man in the country.
你哥是个好人，艾德格
Your brother's a good man, Edgar...
但你才能光宗耀祖
...but you wiII restore our famiIy  to greatness.
艾德格
Edgar?
艾德格，我吵到你了吗？
Edgar? Am I boring you?
我在听，妈，你把女佣开除了
I'm Iistening, Mother. You fired the maid.
我叫她工作做完就能走人
I toId her when she was through,  she couId quit.
我可不付钱给冒失鬼  所有黑人都公然造反
I'm not paying for her impudence.  The whoIe Negro race is in open revoIt.
- 我能展开调查  - 让他们太安逸了
- I couId open an investigation.  - Gotten too comfortabIe.
妈，有听到吗？我能展开调查
Did you hear what I said?  I said I couId open an investigation.
说明一下
Say what you mean.
帕玛先生今天找我参加一场会议  跟布尔什维克党开战了
Mr. PaImer caIIed me into a meeting today.  The war against the BoIsheviks has begun.
他坚持我带领新的反激进部门
He's insisted that I Iead  a new anti- radicaI division.
你有表现出雀跃吗？
Did you Ieap Iike a dog?
我告诉他  这或许是美国所面对最大的威胁
I toId him this is the greatest  threat our nation has ever faced...
我无法接受此职务  除非我确信能有成果
...and I cannot take the job unIess  I feeI certain I can be effective.
很好，但你会接受
WeII done. But you'II take it.
年薪三千元，妈
Three thousand a year, Mother.
我得替你买新衣服  不能再穿像这样了
I've got to get new cIothes.  You can't Iook Iike that anymore.
才四小时，我就有四十个嫌犯的名字
I have 40 names of suspected radicaIs  aIready in onIy four hours.
月底大概会有一万个名字
I shouId have 10,000  by end of the month.
我会有自己的人手  值得信任的探员们
And I have my own staff, trusted agents.
艾德格，你有抽烟吗？
Edgar, are you smoking?
- 我抽不惯，妈  - 听医生的话
- Doesn't come naturaIIy, Mother.  - Listen to the doctor.
这个重担会使你容易焦虑
With this new burden,  your nerves couId get the better of you.
不要沦落成你爸那样
You don't want to end up Iike your father.
去抽一根，扶你爸进房间
Go and try one now.  You can put your father in his room.
我得出门用晚餐
I have to get ready for dinner.
你今晚不陪我？
Are you abandoning me tonight?
我跟一位打字员有约，她很有条理
It's with a typist. She's very organized.
算是约会吗？
Is it a date?
应该是，应该是
I think so. I think so.
我要带她去看  我在国会图书馆编的卡片目录
I'm gonna show her my oId card cataIog  system at the Library of Congress.
追求她
Romance her.
打蓝色领带
Wear a bIue tie.
你打蓝色领带好帅气
You Iook so handsome in your bIue tie.
看这天花板
Look at the ceiIing.
好美
It's incredibIe.
我从没来过这里
I've never been here before.
（国会图书馆）
我协助整理这里
I heIped organize it.
每本书都有各自的索引卡
See, every item is assigned  its own index card...
编上专属的独特代码
...with its own unique code...
指出书名、作者、位置和主题
...indicating the titIe, author,  Iocation, and topic.
过去要花几天的时间才找得到  现在只需几分钟
What used to take days to Iocate  now onIy takes a matter of minutes.
来吧，随便举个作者或主题
Go on. Give me an author  or a topic. Anything.
“言行失检”
Indiscretion.
什么时代？
What era?
现代
Present day.
好，替我计时
Good. Time me.
快找到了
AImost there, heh.
你怎么知道我不是指政治方面？
How do you know I didn't mean  poIiticaI indiscretion?
你想的话，我能重新开始
WeII, if you'd Iike,  I can start aII over again.
这样就行了
This wiII do.
我花多久时间？
How Iong did I take?
一分十秒
One minute, 10 seconds.
想像每位美国公民都可独立辨识
Now imagine if every citizen in this country  were uniqueIy identifiabIe...
有专属的卡片和号码，比如指纹
...by their own card and number,  say, the pattern on their fingers.
如果有人犯罪，我们很快就能逮人
Imagine how quickIy we couId find them  if they committed a crime.
十分令人佩服，约翰
It's aII very impressive, John.
那你想待在这里或去别的地方？
WeII, wouId you Iike to stay here  or wouId you Iike to go somewhere eIse?
由你决定
It's up to you.
胡佛先生
Mr. Hoover.
我不确定你哪来这种想法
I'm not sure where you think  this is headed.
请见谅
Right, of course.
甘帝小姐
Miss Gandy.
我知道我们才认识对方不久
I know we've onIy known each other  a brief time...
但我确定你会是最好的伴侣
...but you wouId  make the finest of companions.
你的坚强、人格和教育程度
Your strength, your character,  your education.
你在嘲弄我吗？
Are you poking fun at me?
不是…当然不是
No. No, no, no. No, no, of course not.
那胡佛先生，请起来
Then pIease, Mr. Hoover, stand up.
我希望你不会把这件事
I'd appreciate it  if you wouIdn't share this...
告诉打字组的其他女生
...with any of the other women  in the typing pooI.
当然不会
No, of course not.
好，我能请教，是不是…
AII right. May I ask what- -  What....
你有发现我人格中的某些缺点？
What particuIar fIaw  you seem to find in my character?
没有，我们才刚认识
No. We just met.
当然了
Right, of course.
但我看人很快也很准
But I beIieve that I am a fast  and accurate judge of character.
我们只约会三次，但我够了解你
We've gone out three times,  but I don't need more.
不像多数人  我能立刻看出人的本质
Most peopIe do, but I don't.  I see peopIe right off for what they are.
还有请叫我艾德格，我妈都这样叫
And pIease, caII me Edgar.  It's what my mother uses.
- 艾德格？  - 什么？
- Edgar?  - Yes?
你能守密吗？
Can you keep a secret?
可以，当然，我保证
Yes. Of course. You have my word.
我没兴趣结婚，我以工作为先
I'm not interested in getting married.  My work comes first.
那或许你会考虑当我的私人秘书
Then perhaps you wouId consider  a position as my personaI secretary.
好
Yes.
我们走吧？
ShaII we?
书要归位
The book.
对喔
Right.
女士优先
After you.
我协助整理图书馆的方式  如同重整调查局
HOOVER: I heIped organize that Iibrary  just as I did this Bureau.
许多人说两者都不必要
And many said we didn't need either.
改革创新者通常不会被赞扬
you see, innovators  aren't often ceIebrated.
刚开始不会
Not at first.
甘帝小姐
Miss Gandy.
肯尼迪家的蠢小子又打来烦了
The nitwit Kennedy chiId  rang his baby buzzer again.
或许他想换尿布
Perhaps he'd Iike a fresh diaper.
要我问司法部长有何需求吗？
ShouId I find out what  the Attorney GeneraI needs?
不，我要洛杉矶录音的完整抄本
No, I want the compIeted transcripts  of the Los AngeIes recordings.
我收到时，我们再回应他
When I receive those,  then we'II answer his buzzer.
好的
Very good.
艾德格，史密斯探员回来了
Edgar, Agent Smith is back.
他有一些帕玛攻击案的问题
He, uh, has some questions  about the PaImer Raids.
要我打发他走吗？
ShouId I teII him to go?
海伦，你喜欢他吗？
HeIen, do you Iike him?
我对他还没有看法
I don't have an opinion of him yet.
我喜欢他，我信任他
WeII, I Iike him. I trust him.
- 我在会客室替他准备  - 不…
- I'II set him up in your outer office.  - No. No, no, no.
在这里替他准备张桌子
Bring him a desk in here.
早在1920年  我如何保护人民不受伤害？
HOOVER: But in 1920,  how couId I protect us from anyone?
我搬进这办公室前，我们毫无权力
Before I moved to this office,  we were powerIess.
几乎没有联邦法、无权持枪
We had few federaI Iaws,  no right to carry firearms...
正合国会的意
...and Congress Iiked it that way.
罪犯逍遥法外  但没有法律禁止持续追踪他们
CriminaIs ran free, but there was no Iaw  against keeping track of them...
所以我自行做出决定
...so I made a decision on my own.
我汇编注记卡以及超过五千个名字
I compiIed note cards  and over five thousand names...
并找来华府唯一…
...and caIIed the one department  in Washington...
仍拥有少数联邦权力的部门
...that stiII heId a smaII piece  of untested power.
是劳工部吗？驱逐出境的权力？
Was that the Department of Labor?  The power to deport, sir?
但只驱逐符合两项规范的人
But onIy to deport those  who checked two boxes.
必须是外国公民且企图危害美国
They had to be foreign citizens and they  had to be working to harm our country.
他们有跟您合作吗？
And they cooperated with you?
当然没有
Of course not.
在华府没人会大方分享权力
No one freeIy shares power  in Washington, D.C., Agent Smith.
你是告诉我在我证实…
PALMER: There is no Iaw  under which you can issue a warrant...
外国人需强制驱逐时
...for the arrest of an aIien...
你无法律权限取得拘票让我逮人？
...when I have certified that  he is subject to deportation?
司法部长，没有证据就不行
Without any evidence,  Mr. Attorney GeneraI, no.
- 这涉及法律程序  - 法律程序？
- There exists a due process of Iaw.  - Due process of Iaw?
- 要是对美国造成威胁呢？  - 是有可能对美国造成威胁…
- What about the threat?  - There might be a threat- -
有可能？
Might be?
好，是会对美国造成威胁
Fine. There is a threat to our country.
但无犯罪证据就无驱逐理由
But with no proof of a crime,  there's no cause for deportation.
我们等着瞧
We'II see about that.
我会再找你
You'II be hearing from me.
但他们的首脑之一，卡莫尼提
HOOVER:  But one of their heads was a Mr. Caminetti.
他受够司法部，但更痛恨一个人
He was weary of our Justice Department,  but he hated one person even more.
我是天生的革命者
I am a revoIutionist by nature...
因此…
...and as such...
我声称有权反叛和抵抗
...I cIaim the right to rebeI  and resist invasion...
一切的胁迫和暴力侵犯
...by aII means, force incIuded.
艾玛高曼，激进运动的英雄
HOOVER: Emma GoIdman. She was the hero  of the radicaI movement.
只要我替卡莫尼提逮到艾玛高曼  他会毫不考虑的驱逐她
If I couId hand Caminetti Emma GoIdman,  he wouId deport her without a thought.
但她是美国公民
But she was a citizen.
您想要暂停吗？
WouId you Iike to stop, sir?
不必
No.
你现在很难想像，但曾有一段时期
I know it's hard for you to imagine today,  but there was a time...
当时一般美国人  害怕自身的安危和生存
...when the average American feared  for their safety and survivaI, Agent Smith.
在芝加哥，共产党劳工发动罢工  在煤矿关闭电源
HOOVER: In Chicago, a coaI strike started  by communist Iabor shut off aII the power.
接着发生暴动
Riots foIIowed.
休战纪念日，在华盛顿森特利亚
And on Armistice Day  in CentraIia, Washington...
刚从战区返回的军人  被激进分子杀害
...veterans fresh back from the war  were murdered by radicaIs.
红色革命侵入我们的领土
[GRUNTS]  HOOVER:  The red revoIution had arrived on our soiI.
不，我们不能逐一铲除
No, no. We can't take them down  one by one.
这样他们会转入地下  每位参议员就会收到炸弹包裹
They'II go underground and we'II have  a bomb inside every senator's maiIbox.
我们要同步袭击，一次一网打尽
We need to have a simuItaneous raid,  hitting aII of them at once.
- 他们是谁？  - 这就是你们要查明的
- Who are ''they''?  - You're here to find out.
现在听好  我要美国每个激进分子的资料卡
Now Iisten, I want a card on every  radicaI person in this country.
靠墙，各位，谢谢
Against the waII, gentIemen.
查出名字、国籍、团体、言论
I wanna know who, where they're from,  what group, what they say.
有前科的人吗？
Who have aIready committed crimes?
我不在乎前科，只在乎意图  靠墙，各位，谢谢
I care more whether they intend to.  Against the waII, gentIemen, thank you.
- 我们小队有多少人？  - 目前只有你们四人
- How many are on our team?  - OnIy you four for now.
我会替柜子装锁
I'II have Iocks instaIIed.
不，那样更会引起注意
No, Miss Gandy.  That wouId bring too much attention.
现在起不要照字母排列
Nothing is to be aIphabeticaIIy ordered.
我要卡片分成主题和种类
I want the cards to be broken down  into subjects and categories.
这种系统一经解释就很容易看穿
Now, this system shouId be easy enough  if expIained.
但不说明，则不可能找到资讯
If not, finding information  shouId prove impossibIe.
还有  谁都别信任，甚至其他探员
And trust no one,  not even our feIIow agents.
有一半的同事在黑白两道拿钱
HaIf our coIIeagues are on both sides  of the payroII.
但是我们调查的罪行并不是罪  而是理念
But the crimes we're investigating  aren't crimes, they're ideas.
如果你的理念…
WeII, if your idea- -
靠墙，各位，谢谢
Against the waII, gentIemen. Thank you.
如果你的理念牵涉到美国  以及推翻美国政府的阴谋
If your idea is to come into our country  and pIot the overthrow of our government...
这的确就是犯罪
...then, yes, indeed, that is a crime.
高曼女士嫁给美国公民
Mrs. GoIdman married a U.S. citizen.
她丈夫从不探她的监  反而是这个男人…
The man she married hasn't visited  her once in prison, yet this man...
她婚后就同居，每晚去找她
...the man she's Iived with since her  wedding, he visits nightIy.
告诉我，约翰，要是我们  突袭名单上的人却无斩获…
What happens when  we raid this Iist of yours and find nothing?
没枪和炸弹的无辜者却被驱逐？
No guns, no bombs,  just innocent peopIe deported.
在国内的每个角落
From every corner of this nation,  the American peopIe...
美国人民催促司法部长  对于暴力要做出回应
...have urged the Attorney GeneraI  to do something about this...
帮助美国恢复和平与荣耀
...and return the United States  back to peace.
我乐于转达你的异议给帕玛本人
Now, I'm happy to send your objections  to Mr. PaImer himseIf...
不过你得先揭露高曼的假结婚
...but, in the meantime,  expose Miss GoIdman's sham marriage...
你也要改变你的穿着
...and you wiII change that suit of yours.
- 你说什么，约翰？  - 你的穿着…
- Pardon me, John?  - Your suit, sir, your suit.
这里不是酒店
This isn't a saIoon.
你要尊重自己，但更重要的是…
Have respect for yourseIf,  but, more importantIy...
尊重这个部门
...have respect for this department.
甘帝小姐
Miss Gandy?
高曼小姐，你是无政府主义者吗？
MAN:  Miss GoIdman, are you an anarchist?
我婉拒回答
I decIine to answer.
你否认你是无政府主义者？
MAN:  Do you deny that you are an anarchist?
我婉拒回答
I decIine to answer.
你相信能以武力或暴力  推翻美国政府？
Do you beIieve in the overthrow  of the government of the United States?
我拒绝回答
I refuse to answer.
你鼓吹暗杀公务官员？
Do you advocate the assassination  of pubIic officiaIs?
我拒绝回答
I refuse to answer.
这位外国人拒绝回答  关于拘票所指控的任何问题
This aIien has refused to answer questions  pertaining to the charges in the warrant...
尽管已给她充分的机会
...notwithstanding the fact that  every opportunity was afforded her.
我建议驱逐出境
I recommend deportation.
就这样，我们创了先例
HOOVER:  And just Iike that, we had our precedent.
艾德格  我该安排情人节的派特森之旅吗？
Edgar, shouId I arrange our traveI  to Paterson on VaIentine's Day?
当然好，甘帝小姐
Yes, of course, Miss Gandy.
2月14日  我搭火车去纽泽西州派特森
HOOVER: I took the train to Paterson,  New Jersey, on February 14th.
如果我能当场逮到这些激进分子
If I couId catch these radicaIs red- handed...
劳工部就得把他们全部遣送回家
...then the Labor Department wouId have  to put them aII on boats back home.
于是调查局探员跟当地警察
So agents of the Bureau,  aIongside IocaI poIice...
开始突袭共产激进派的聚集地
...began raiding gathering pIaces  of known communist radicaIs...
范围扩及全国
...aII across this country.
这些人武装且暴力
These peopIe are armed and vioIent.
他们为避免落网，准备大开杀戒
They're prepared to kiII to avoid capture.
带着枪，快点
HOOVER:  Take one. Go on.
- 我们能用枪吗？  - 就当我送的礼物
- Are we aIIowed to use these, sir?  - These are gifts.
没有法律禁止我们使用自己的枪
There is no Iaw that prevents us  from using our own weapons.
各位，拿枪
GentIemen, grab your guns.
赶快
GentIemen, quickIy.
行动
Let's move.
警察！这是突袭
OFFICER:  PoIice! This is a raid!
他要从窗户逃了  阻止他！
OFFICER:  He's going for the window, stop him!
够了！
That's enough!
传单完全相符  我们解决了爆炸案
HOOVER:  The IeafIets matched exactIy.  We'd soIved the bombings.
最后我们逮捕近四千名共产激进派
And, in the end, we arrested nearIy  4000 communist radicaIs...
并驱逐其中五百人  在渺小的机会中完成危险的任务
...and deported over 500 of them.
因为我最关心的是国家安全  这宗旨从未改变
It was accompIished against great odds  and at great personaI periI.
他们发现伪造报刊  五支枪、两支自动步枪
They found the counterfeiting press,  five pistoIs, two automatics.
在特顿  发现火药、铜、黄铜丝和电池
And in Trenton, they found gunpowder,  copper, brass wire, and batteries.
- 炸弹工厂  - 对
- A bomb factory.  - Yes.
目前在底特律捉到120人  费城41人，这里17人
One hundred and twenty arrests in Detroit,  41 in PhiIadeIphia, and 1 7 here so far.
但参与逮捕的探员全丢了饭碗吧？
SMITH: But everyone in the Bureau invoIved  Iost their job, correct?
甚至帕玛本人
Even PaImer himseIf?
有些是，但从这里学到一课
HOOVER:  Some did, and there's the Iesson.
阻止炸弹，带来和平
you see, the bombs stopped,  and peace came.
美国人已忘记曾有的威胁
The American peopIe had forgotten  there ever was a threat.
所以当政治敌手攻击帕玛
So when poIiticaI adversaries  attacked PaImer...
因他保卫美国以摆脱共产主义
...for trying to protect this nation  from communism...
国人默许这种事发生
...our countrymen aIIowed it to happen.
因为就像现今  人们已忘记炸弹、残杀和恐惧
Because Iike today, they've forgotten  the bombs, the bIood, the fear.
如果你是主导  为何解雇帕玛，而不是你？
SMITH: But why PaImer and not you,  if you orchestrated the raids?
我才24岁，史密斯探员  我只是听命行事
I was 24 years oId, Agent Smith.  I was just foIIowing orders.
我了解，长官
I understand, sir.
如果我们没行动  你可能就出生在共产国家
And if we hadn't, you may very weII  have been born into a communist state...
而不是如今你所爱的国家
...rather than the country you Iove today.
- 我说的对吧？  - 当然，长官
- Am I right?  - Of course, sir.
艾德格？
TOLSON:  Edgar?
别管他
Ignore him.
艾德格？
TOLSON:  Edgar?
我在开会，托尔森先生，快好了
I am in a meeting, Mr. ToIson.  I'II be out in a moment.
别忘记你跟司法部长有约
Don't forget about your appointment  with the Attorney GeneraI, Edgar.
档案还没完成，托尔森先生  请走开
FiIes are not yet compIeted, Mr. ToIson.  PIease go away.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢您，长官  很抱歉，今晚我会完成这一章
Thank you, sir. I apoIogize.  I'II finish this chapter tonight.
很好，史密斯探员
Very weII, Agent Smith.
在调查局学院  听过我当上局长的故事吗？
In the Academy, do they teII the story  of how I got here?
听过，新司法部长请您到办公室
Yes, sir. Uh, you were caIIed into  the new Attorney GeneraI's office....
- 哈伦费斯克史东  - 对，司法部长史东
- HarIan Fiske Stone.  - Yes, sir, Attorney GeneraI Stone.
他请您到办公室并要您坐下，长官
He caIIed you into his office  and toId you to sit down, sir.
部长，芝加哥有十几个空缺
Sir, there are over a dozen vacancies  in Chicago.
由于抢劫率升高
And with the robbery rates rising,  it wouId profit the Bureau...
应该填补空缺以挽救本局声誉
...to start fiIIing vacancies  and make recoveries.
我有几柜存放潜在嫌犯的档案  加上国会听证会，我…
I have fiIes on potentiaI suspects,  and with a congressionaI hearing- -
别说了，小子  不是你召开会议的，是我，坐下
Lower the trebIe, son. You didn't caII  this meeting, I did. Sit down.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
你在这里的同事都走了
Everyone you've worked with here is gone.  And there's a reason for that.
这有理可循，局里风气过于腐败  同意吗？
This Bureau is of exceedingIy bad odor.  WouId you agree?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
别介意，但你似乎没有社交生活
And, no offense,  you seem to have no sociaI Iife.
没有妻子或女友  就我所知，完全没朋友
No wife, no girIfriend.  As far as I can teII, no paIs at aII.
没错，长官
That is accurate, sir.
你一股脑儿投入  杂乱无章的指纹计划
And you're shameIessIy distracted  by this hodgepodge fingerprinting affair.
只要我们能集中指纹  我保证不会杂乱无章
Sir, it wouIdn't be hodgepodge if we couId  centraIize the prints here, I assure you.
这充其量是投机性科学
It's a specuIative science at best.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
为什么大家叫你 “快人” ？
And why do they caII you Speed?
谁那样叫我？
Who caIIs me that?
所有人，显然是在你背后叫
They aII do, behind your back, evidentIy.
我十岁时因为送杂货而有这名号
I gained a reputation for deIivering  groceries when I was 10 years oId.
我是同区送货最快的人  那只是绰号
I was the fastest in the neighborhood.  It was just a nickname.
你确定不是因讲话太快？
You sure it's not for the way you taIk?
或许，长官
Perhaps, sir.
年轻人，我要你担任临时调查局长
Young man, I want you to be acting  director of the Bureau of Investigation.
我会接受职务，史东先生，但…  有一些条件
I wiII take the job, Mr. Stone,  but onIy on certain conditions.
说来听听
What are they?
本局必须脱离政治  不会成为政客利用的工具
The Bureau must be divorced from poIitics  and not be a catchaII for poIiticaI hacks.
新人必须是大学毕业
Recruits must be coIIege- educated.
唯才适用
Appointments must be based on merit.
升迁要凭实力
Promotions wiII be made on proven abiIity.
还有…本局只会对…
And, weII, the Bureau wiII be  responsibIe onIy to you, sir...
司法部长您负责
...the Attorney GeneraI.
我给你这职务，就因为这些条件
I wouIdn't give you the job  under any other conditions.
就这样，祝今天愉快
That's aII. Good day.
谢谢，长官
WeII, thank you, sir.
我决定立刻开除本局中
I am determined to summariIy dismiss  from this Bureau...
被我发现有酗酒习惯的员工
...any empIoyee whom I find  induIging in the use of intoxicants.
我相信要成为调查局一员
It is my beIief that when a man  becomes a part of this Bureau...
就必须以身作则  于公于私皆是
...he must so conduct himseIf,  both officiaIIy and unofficiaIIy...
任何可能被批评的个人行为
...as to eIiminate even  the sIightest possibiIity of criticism...
就算再小也不可为
...as to his conduct.
- 你叫什么名字？  - 威廉探员
- And what is your name, sir?  - Agent WiIIiams, sir.
- 幸会，威廉探员  - 我也是
- PIeasure to meet you, Agent WiIIiams.  - You too, sir.
你的名字？
And your name?
卡佛瑞探员，长官
Agent Caffrey, sir.
- 卡佛瑞探员，你有何任务？  - 我今天要去堪萨斯城
- Your assignment?  - I'm headed to Kansas City...
协助搜寻在逃银行抢犯
...to aid in the search  for bank robber Frank Nash, sir.
那是危险的工作  你为国效命
Mm, that is dangerous work,  and when you return...
回来时会受到表扬
...you wiII be rewarded for your service.
你还是喜欢留胡子，史托克探员
You stiII fancy faciaI hair, Agent Stokes?
这样才有女人缘
- The Iadies appreciate it.  - Hmm.
我想女人的意见比调查局重要
And I suppose the Iadies' opinions  are more important than the Bureau's?
并不是
No.
局长
Sir.
或许你更适合警局
Perhaps you are better suited  for the poIice force...
而不是调查局
...than the Bureau of Investigations.
我在司法部和调查局工作七年了
I've been with the Department and  the Bureau for seven years.
几乎跟你一样久
AImost as Iong as you.
不对
No.
你在老调查局工作七年  那个调查局是过去式了
You were with the oId Bureau seven years,  and that Bureau is now gone, sir.
你也是
And so are you.
我很快开除所有未达标准的探员
HOOVER: I quickIy dismissed aII agents  that did not fit my standards:
教育、体能
Education, physicaI fitness...
但最重要的是  忠诚
...but, above aII, IoyaIty.
我订做两件  同样剪裁，不同花样
I've had two made.  Same cut, different pattern.
还有两套西装，周五会送来
And two suits for you.  They'II be deIivered on Friday.
谢谢，妈
Thank you, Mother.
是白金戒
It's pIatinum...
六颗钻和单颗星彩蓝宝石
...six diamonds and a star sapphire.
美极了，妈，谢谢
- Heh.  - It's absoIuteIy beautifuI, Mother.  Thank you.
我告诉左邻右舍你的事了
I've toId the whoIe neighborhood  about you. They aII know.
不，我该节制，我体重直线上升
No, I shouIdn't,  I've been gaining weight, Mother.
是变结实，男人结实才好
It's soIid weight. There's nothing wrong  with soIid weight on a man.
- 好吧  - 我非常以你为傲，艾德格
- AII right.  - I'm so incredibIy proud of you, Edgar.
我要替你制作纪录本
I'm starting an aIbum for you.
我要收集所有报导，这只是开始
I'm gonna put everything in it.  This is just the beginning.
“约翰胡佛被任命临时调查局长”
''Johnny Hoover appointed acting director  of the Bureau of Investigations.''
你看
Can you read that?
你以舅舅为傲吗？
You proud of your uncIe?
各位
MAN:  GentIemen.
我帮你介绍，跟我来
I want to introduce you. Come with me.
艾德格，很高兴见到你
Edgar, good to see you.
很高兴见到你，罗伦斯
HOOVER:  Good to see you, Lawrence.
这位是克莱德托尔森先生
I'd Iike to introduce you  to Mr. CIyde ToIson.
刚从乔治华盛顿大学毕业  取得法律学位
Graduated from George Washington  University tonight with a Iaw degree.  HOOVER:  Hmm.
恭喜，托尔森先生
CongratuIations, Mr. ToIson.
谢谢，胡佛先生  你想必是我们最杰出的校友之一
Thank you, Mr. Hoover. I beIieve you are  one of our most distinguished aIumni.
我是，我也是在那拿到法律学位
I did, yes. I, uh, do have a degree  from the schooI, yes.
我欣赏你的服装，托尔森先生  你该向他学习，罗伦斯
I was admiring your suit, Mr. ToIson.  You shouId take a Iesson, Lawrence.
谢谢，是在葛芬柯百货订做的
Thank you, sir. It's a custom cut,  from GarfinkeI's department store.
托尔森先生，你有名片吗？
Do you have a card, Mr. ToIson?
我有，当然
I do, yes, of course.
请指教
Here you go.
很高兴见到你，罗伦斯
Good to see you, Lawrence.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
“教育良好，高度推荐  保证服务五年”
''WeII- educated, highIy recommended,  wiIIing to guarantee five years service.
“家人在纽约，有个新生儿”
Has a famiIy in New York  and a new baby.''
不面试
No interview.
因为家人在纽约或新生儿？
The famiIy in New York or the baby?
甘帝小姐，五年不够  我们需要愿意奉献一辈子的人
Miss Gandy, five years is not enough.  We need men wiIIing to dedicate their Iives.
目前多少人了？
How many is that so far?
320人被拒绝，21人面试
- That's 320 denied and 21 interviews.  - Hmm.
有收到一位托尔森先生的申请吗？
Did we receive an appIication  from a Mr. ToIson?
有
Yes.
他的推荐函说他有自信、稳重
Yes, his report states  he has confidence, poise...
他用词完美
...his diction is exceIIent.
虽然体格健壮  但不喜欢粗重工作
But aIthough physicaIIy fitted for it,  might be dispIeased with rugged work.
他对调查局唯一的兴趣  是这工作有利于他开法律事务所
His onIy interest is to gain experience  that wouId benefit a private Iaw practice.
在任职期间，他没兴趣待在…
And he has no interest in being here  for any period of time...
要冒风险的工作岗位
...which wouId render  empIoyment specuIative.
他是有推荐信
He did receive  a Ietter of recommendation...
来自战争部长的高级助理
...from the executive assistant  of the Secretary of War.
太棒了，甘帝小姐
That's fantastic, Miss Gandy.
好，这里提到托尔森先生  对于女人不甚感兴趣
Yes. It mentions here that Mr. ToIson  showed no particuIar interest in women.
同样地，我们几位最佳的探员  就是因为没家累而表现优异
Then again, some of our best agents exceI  because they have no famiIy encumbrance.
你说的对，安排面试
Yes, you're right. Set up an interview.
你知道问题出在哪，甘帝小姐？
You know what the probIem is,  Miss Gandy?
这些应征的人，他们不会仰望我
These men, they don't- -   They don't Iook up to me.
没这回事
Of course they do.
我不是在比喻，他们不会抬头看我
I don't mean figurativeIy.  I mean they don't Iook up to me.
如果面谈时你能坐在书桌后方
WeII, if you couId conduct the entire  interview from behind your desk...
而不是在办公室来回走的话  我可以改善这状况
...instead of waIking about the office,  I couId correct that.
当然了
Indeed.
甘帝小姐  假设我有权势人物的秘密情报
Miss Gandy, suppose I had information  on someone in a position of power...
是不利的情报
...harmfuI information.
摧毁这类情报违背我的本意
It goes against my nature  to destroy such information...
但我也不信任归在一般档案中
...but I don't trust it  in the generaI fiIes either.
我能托付给你吗？
CouId I trust it with you?
如果我们要开设一个机密档案？
If we were to create a confidentiaI fiIe?
当然，艾德格
Of course, Edgar.
谢谢你，甘帝小姐
Thank you, Miss Gandy.
情报就是力量
HOOVER:  Information is power.
保护我们1919年摆脱共产党
It protected us from the communists  in 1919...
从此联邦调查局警觉地收集、编制  和保存情报
...and since has been vigiIantIy coIIected,  organized, and maintained by our FBI.
司法部长肯尼迪办公室
WOMAN:  Attorney GeneraI Kennedy's Office.
这个壁炉是原本就有或加装的？
Did you aIways have this firepIace  or did you have it put in?
加装的
KENNEDY:  It was put in.
你干嘛在那房子装窃听器？
What were you doing with wiretaps  in that house?
你要我追查这个组织的犯罪线索
You asked that I pursue this  organized crime eIement, Mr. Kennedy...
我谨慎地照办
...and I did so, sir, with diIigence.
- 你有用壁炉吗？  - 很少
- Do you use the firepIace?  - RareIy.
还有谁听了录音？
Who eIse has heard the recording?
我归在私人且机密的档案中
I have fiIed the matter  personaI and confidentiaI.
我是唯一能取得的人
I'm the onIy person with access to it.
我要你追查真正的威胁
Mr. Hoover, I asked you to pursue  a reaI threat.
你却公开否认这组织犯罪的存在
Instead, you've pubIicIy denied  the existence of organized crime...
现在又利用恐吓手段
...and now this gross dispIay  of intimidation.
司法部长先生，我只是听命行事
Mr. Attorney GeneraI,  I was onIy foIIowing orders.
我们在洛杉矶民宅的地下室窃听
We bugged the basement of a home  in Los AngeIes...
那是已知的罪犯聚集地
...that was a known gathering pIace  for Iawbreakers.
我哪知道一名东德共产党员…
How was I to know that an East German  communist wouId be down there...
会在那里跟令兄做爱  堂堂的美国总统
...having sex with your brother,  the President of the United States?
不斩来使，我只是来保护你们俩
Do not shoot the messenger, sir.  I am here to protect you both.
请记住这点
Remember that.
你要我怎样？
What do you want from me?
如果这个讯息被公开
If this information were to go pubIic...
令兄的领导力会受到广泛质疑
...it wouId create widespread distrust  in your brother's Ieadership capabiIities.
总之，我的首要考量是我国的福祉
And above aII eIse, I hoId the weII- being  of our country paramount.
那我能怎么帮你，胡佛先生？
So how may I heIp you, Mr. Hoover?
若我要追查你认定是威胁的线索
WeII, if I am to pursue the eIements  that you consider a threat...
我谦卑地要求你让我  有相同的权力和途径
...I humbIy request that you aIIow me  the same power and access...
跟踪我视为立即威胁的团体
...to foIIow the groups that I see  as an immediate threat.
现在不再是1920年了
It's not 1920 anymore.
你知道史丹利李文森吧？
You know who StanIey Levinson is, sir?
一名律师
A Iawyer.
最高层级的白人共产党律师
A white, communist Iawyer  organizing at the highest IeveIs...
包括南基督教领协
...incIuding the SCLC.
他们的团体正在壮大
Now, their group is growing.
他们只求私利
They are entireIy seIf- serving...
他们的领袖公开批判本部门
...and their Ieadership is openIy criticaI  of this department here.
你有读我给你的便条？
Did you read the memos that I sent?
没有，还没有
No, no, I can't say that I have.
上面有写，肯尼迪先生
It says right here, Mr. Kennedy.
他们声称我们
They cIaim we are...
“连最坏、最重的案件都无法定罪”
...''unabIe to get convictions in even  the worst, most heinous crimes...''
还有，我们 “畏缩当局的压力”
...and that we have ''faItered under  the pressure, compIexities...
“混乱和责任”
...and responsibiIities of our office,''  in print.
- 就写在《华盛顿邮报》  - 你不能忍受一点批判？
- Right here in ''The Washington Post.''  - You can't bear a IittIe criticism?
视对方目的为何而定
WeII, it depends on what their aim is.
他们正获取可观的势力
They are gaining considerabIe power.
他们的优先考量只注重自身利益
Their priorities are singuIarIy focused  on their own issues.
还试图煽动叛乱
They are trying to incite revoIt.
老实说，他们的说法  比较针对贵局而非本部
FrankIy, they sound more criticaI  of your office than mine.
共产主义有了新面貌，今非昔比
There's a new face to communism,  Edgar, and this isn't it.
现在的共产威胁来自国外非国内
Communism is a foreign threat now,  not domestic.
肯尼迪先生，在你还没出生前
Mr. Kennedy,  before you were even born...
我就听米契帕玛说过类似言论
...I heard that very same argument  from a Mr. MitcheII PaImer.
可知让他改变心意的代价？
Do you know what it took  to change his mind?
一颗炸弹
A bomb.
1919年，他若多待在摇椅上五分钟
If he wouId have sat in his rocking chair  five more minutes in 1919...
够幸运的话还能找到完整的食指
...we'd have been Iucky enough  to find an intact index finger.
我不希望旧事重演在你和令兄上
Now, I do not want that to happen  to you or your brother, sir.
我们大有理由各取所需
There's no reason  we both can't get what we want.
我们能向国内外双方宣战，懂吗？
We can wage a war on two fronts, sir.  You understand?
你可以离开了，胡佛先生
You can go now, Mr. Hoover.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
请把抄本留下给我
PIease Ieave the transcripts here with me.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
尽管拿给令兄看
Oh, and feeI free and share them  with your brother.
喔，也让他知道我有保留副本
Oh, and Iet him know that I have  a copy of my own in safekeeping.
你四点的约来了
- Unh.  - Your 4:00 is here, sir.
谢谢，甘帝小姐，请他进来
Thank you, Miss Gandy.  Send him right in, thank you.
请坐，托尔森先生
PIease, have a seat, Mr. ToIson.
- 胡佛先生，谢谢给我机会  - 别客气
- Mr. Hoover, thank you for this opportunity.  - Yes. PIease.
- 请坐  - 谢谢您
- Have a seat.  - Thank you, sir.
你的申请书上有几个问题
There were severaI probIems  with your appIication, Mr. ToIson...
事实上，你毫无表现出…
...not the Ieast of which is the fact  that you did not show...
本局要求的特质，还有…
...the proper requirement to the Bureau...
保护美国人民和国策的特有使命
[STAMMERING]  ...nor the proper dedication  to protecting the American peopIe...  ...and the American way.
容我提醒，这不是你…
May I remind you  that this is not a pIatform...
私人创业营利的跳板
...to a fatter paycheck in private practice,  Mr. ToIson?
托尔森先生，有问题吗？
Is there something the matter,  Mr. ToIson?
没有，先生
No, sir.
运动是所有探员的要求吗？
Is exercise a requirement  for aII agents, sir?
对，我们的所有探员  需要处于最佳体能状态
Yes. AII our agents need to be  in top physicaI condition.
我们随时随地要  智取和战胜国民公敌
We must outsmart and outmatch  the pubIic enemy at every turn.
当然了
Yes, of course.
那您固定做什么运动？
So, uh, what routine do you do, sir?
伏地挺身、仰卧起坐和交互蹲跳
Push- ups, sit- ups, and squatting.
我懂了
I see.
胡佛先生，我来调窗帘
WouId you Iike me to fix the curtain?
或者我可以开窗  我运动后习惯空气流通
Or perhaps I couId open a window.  I aIways prefer  a IittIe bit of air after exercise.
您呢？
Don't you?
请便
If it wouId pIease you.
我在履历上可能有不足之处
And, sir, where I may faII short  in terms of resume...
但我在诚信上远胜于其他人
...I apparentIy far exceed  the rest in terms of honesty.
我不像其他人为录取而说谎  对，我终究想要开业
I didn't Iie to get this appointment, sir.  Like the rest, yes,  I wouId Iike to start a practice...
不过只要出现适当机会  我也会卖力
...but I couId be persuaded otherwise  if the right opportunities were to arise.
有道理，托尔森先生
Fair enough, Mr. ToIson.
有道理
Fair enough.
（葛芬柯百货）
袖子似乎是正确长度
These sIeeves seem to be  the correct Iength.
我替你挑了两条领带
I found you two tie options.
这条比较时髦，有点花俏
This one is a bit more fashion- forward...
但我认为很配这套西装的款式和布料
...but it wouId compIement this suit  and cut and fabric.
我觉得有点太花俏
It's too Ioud, don't you think?
太花俏？好，所以我挑了这条备用
Too Ioud? Okay, which is why  I found this one, the backup.
- 比较主管型，或许能说稍微…  - 稍微保守，我同意
- It's a bit more directoriaI, a IittIe bit more- -   - It's a IittIe bit more reserved, I agree.
这个请留作第二选择  谢谢你，克莱德
Let's keep this as a second option, pIease.  Thank you, CIyde.
你是约翰胡佛先生？
Are you Mr. John Hoover?
我是，有问题吗？
I am. Is there a probIem?
看来这位约翰胡佛先生  在本店的信用不良
It seems there's a Mr. John Hoover  whose credit has gone bad with us.
似乎就是你
That wouId appear to be you.
这不是我，我保证
That is not me, sir, on my word.
我妈称我艾德格，我侄女称我JE  我的签名会多个 “E”
My mother caIIs me Edgar, my niece caIIs  me J.E., and I sign John E., not John.
既然你是托尔森先生的朋友
WeII, sir, if you're a friend  of Mr. ToIson's...
就选个名字再申请吧
...just choose one name and reappIy.
好
AII right.
感谢你
Thank you very much.
（约翰艾德格胡佛）
早安，甘帝小姐
Morning, Miss Gandy.
怎样？你不喜欢？
What? You don't Iike it?
胡佛先生…  堪萨斯城发生屠杀
Mr. Hoover,  there's been a massacre in Kansas City.
我们的探员出事了？
One of our own?
卡佛瑞探员？
SpeciaI Agent Caffrey?
给他好看！
MAN:  Let him have it!
到了1930年，共党威胁被击退
HOOVER: By 1930, the communist threat  had been beaten back...
但经济大萧条带来新威胁
...but the Depression had hit  and there was a new threat.
银行抢匪、偷车贼和绑架犯
The bank robber, the car thief,  and the kidnapper.
然而很不幸，如同共产主义  国人的反应不是轻蔑
But, unfortunateIy, as with communism,  America didn't react with scorn.
他们反而把美国黑帮当偶像崇拜
They gave the American gangster  admiration.
不可再忽视鲁莽的武装罪犯
HOOVER: And the defiance by desperate,  armed criminaIs...
蔑视社会和文明力量
...of the forces of society and civiIization  can no Ionger be ignored.
疯子莫蓝和艾尔卡彭是头号公敌
Bugs Moran and AI Capone  top the Iist of pubIic enemies.
环顾四周，他们可能在任何地方
Look around you.  They couId be anywhere.
提醒各位  调查局志在成为人民的守护者
May I remind you that the Bureau of  Investigation seeks to be your protector.
它属于你们  就像你身边的电话触手可及
It beIongs to you. It is as cIose to you  as your nearest teIephone.
有你们的帮助…
And with your heIp....
华纳兄弟影业呈献《国民公敌》
ANNOUNCER: Warner Bros. presents  a Vitaphone production of:  ''The PubIic Enemy.''
詹姆士卡格尼饰演头号公敌
James Cagney pIays  pubIic enemy number one.
原来是你
- Why, you.  - Aah!
- 你又乱许愿了  - 或许你找到更喜欢的人了
TOM:  There you go with that wishing stuff again.  Maybe you found someone  you Iike better.
即将在当地戏院上映
ANNOUNCER:  Coming soon to your neighborhood theater.
太棒了
MAN:  Fantastic.
那年夏天  一宗案件开始把情势导正
That summer, a singIe crime opened  the door to set things right.
琼斯先生，知道是什么吗？
Do you know what that was, Mr. Jones?
抱歉，长官，是什么？
Sorry, sir, what was that?
谁是20世纪至今最有名的人？
Who is the most famous man  of the 20th Century thus far?
乔麦卡锡？
Joe McCarthy, sir?
麦卡锡先生是投机者
Mr. McCarthy was an opportunist...
不是爱国者，琼斯先生
...not a patriot, Mr. Jones.
谁是20世纪至今最有名的人？
Who is the most famous man  of the 20th Century thus far?
最有名？
The most famous?
是您吗？长官
Is that you, sir?
我想此人的名声来自他的事业
WeII, I suppose his notoriety  depends on the fieId that he is in.
他的事业领域在云端
His fieId was in the cIouds.
那就是查尔斯林白了，长官
WeII, then CharIes Lindbergh, sir.
喂？
Yes?
查尔斯林白的幼子从家中被绑架
MAN [OVER PHONE]: CharIes Lindbergh's  baby has been kidnapped from his home.
通报特顿警方，我搭第一班车过去
Send officers from Trenton.  I'II be on the first train.
什么事？
What is it?
查尔斯林白…的幼子被绑架
CharIes Lindbergh- -   Lindbergh's baby's been kidnapped.
你一定要找到他，艾德格
You've got to find him.
他必须活着回家
He has to be brought home aIive.
是，妈
Yes, Mother.
是，妈，我知道
Yes, Mother, I know.
1932年的那天早上  我们抵达林白先生的家
HOOVER: When we arrived at  Mr. Lindbergh's home that morning in 1932...
展开这个将使本局永远改观的调查
...we began an investigation that wouId  forever change our Bureau.
光是今早，连系我们的就有  宝州铁路、威尔罗杰斯
This morning we've heard from  the PennsyIvania RaiIroad, WiII Rogers...
胡佛总统、罗斯福州长、海关部
...President Hoover,  Governor RooseveIt, Customs...
美国邮政和童子军
...the U.S. MaiI, and the Boy Scouts.
全部人离开
HOOVER:  AII of you. Get off of that dirt.
你们在践踏证据  赶快，走开
You're trampIing evidence.  ImmediateIy! Get off!
那里没线索  我们检查过，脚印不清楚
There's nothing there. We checked.  No defined footprints.
看来他穿布质鞋套
It appears he was wearing fabric  on his shoes.
难道脚印的尺寸没有搜证价值？
You don't think the size  couId've heId some vaIue?
他怎么上去的？窗和墙上有痕迹吗？
How did he get up there? Are there  marks on the window and waII as weII?
一百码外发现断成三节的梯子
A Iadder.  We found it 100 yards away.
我们搬到里面了
We moved it inside.
你们搬了？
You moved it?
对，为了保管
Yes, for safekeeping.
恭喜，史瓦考夫先生  你彻底破坏犯罪现场了
CongratuIations, Mr. Schwarzkopf.  You have contaminated the crime scene.
现在请把脚移开这里，谢谢
Now, get your boots off this property.
你有什么资格在这里，这位…
And what right do you have  to be here, Mister, uh...?
艾德格胡佛，调查局局长
J. Edgar Hoover,  director of the Bureau of Investigation.
胡佛总统直接指派我们  以确保调查能成功完成
We've been sent by President Hoover  to ensure the investigation- -
总统授权我们取得所有文件和证据
The president has authorized access  to aII documents and evidence.
胡佛先生，想旁观随你  但是纽泽西不是总统的领地
Mr. Hoover, you're free to observe,  but New Jersey's not the president's domain.
林白先生在哪里？  我想听他对案件的意见
And where is Mr. Lindbergh?  I'd Iike to hear his opinion on the matter.
- 林白先生在后面  - 你先请
- Mr. Lindbergh's around back.  - After you, sir.
他整晚都没睡
He's been up aII night.
林白先生亲自下来见我
HOOVER: Mr. Lindbergh himseIf  came down to meet me.
他跟我握手  并向年轻的调查局表达感谢和信心
He shook my hand and expressed his  gratitude and faith in our young Bureau.
他跌落五尺
He feII five feet.
谁？
Who did?
绑匪，手上抱着小孩
The kidnapper, with the chiId in his arms.
那只是推测，胡佛先生
That's specuIation, Mr. Hoover.
林白先生  如果梯子在人向上爬时断掉
Mr. Lindbergh, sir, if the Iadder had spIit  whiIe the person was on their way up...
梯子就会倒塌  这是误算…
...it wouId have coIIapsed.  You see, it was a miscaIcuIation.
原本上去能承重一人  但下来加了小孩就无法承重
It was meant to bear the weight of a man,  but not the weight of a man and chiId.
我们有其他理论
We have other theories.
勒索信在哪里？
Where's the ransom note?
当然有
Of course.
你也光着手拿信
And you are touching that  with your bare hands as weII?
我们检查过了
We checked.
没有你视如珍宝的指纹
There are none of those finger imprints  that you fancy so vaIuabIe.
请递给我，史瓦考夫先生
PIease hand it over, Mr. Schwarzkopf.
是史瓦考夫上校
SCHWARZKOPF:  That's CoIoneI Schwarzkopf.
准备好五万元，拼错“准备”
''Have 50,000 doIIars ready,''  speIIed R- E- D- Y.
我们会通知送钱的地点
''We wiII inform you where,''  speIIed W- E- R- E, ''to deIiver the money''...
拼错“地点”和 “钱”
...speIIed M- O- N- Y.
我们警告你别公开或报警
''We warn you for making anything pubIic  or for notify the poIice.
所有信函以签名为凭  拼错“签名”
Indication for aII Ietters are signature,''  S- I- N- G, ''singnature.''
三个孔
Three hoIes.
我要这封信和梯子
I want this Ietter and the Iadder.
这里不属于联邦管辖  你要的都给你看了
No jurisdiction.  I've showed what you asked for.
- 你该走了  - 林白先生，听我说…
- It's time for you to go.  - Mr. Lindbergh, pIease....
胡佛先生，心领了  如你所见，一切都在我们控制中
Mr. Hoover, thank you. As you can see,  we have everything under controI.
谢谢，各位
Thank you, gentIemen.
谢谢你的时间，林白先生
Thank you for your time, Mr. Lindbergh.
克莱德
CIyde.
克莱德，我担心他儿子
CIyde, I'm afraid for his boy.
他比较信任当地警察
He trusts the IocaI poIice more than us.
他认为我们都是笨蛋
He thinks we're aII fooIs.
他会甩开警察  自己跟绑匪谈判
He'II go around them too.  He's going to bargain with the kidnappers.
胡佛总统在小孩出事的早上打给我
President Hoover caIIed me the morning  the chiId was taken...
要我在权限内不计代价帮助破案
...and asked me to do whatever was  in my power to soIve this crime.
但调查局的所有权限
But do you know what aII the power  of the Bureau means...
是没有联邦法保障  没有武器、没有逮捕权限
...without federaI Iaws, without arms,  without the abiIity to make arrests?
这样毫无意义
It means nothing.
主席先生，我力主通过“林白法”
Mr. Chairman, I urge passage  of the Lindbergh Law...
明订绑架是联邦罪行
...making kidnapping a federaI offense.
立刻把全国的指纹送到我办公室
To immediateIy deIiver aII the fingerprints  in this country to my office...
让我们建立中央档案
...so that we may create a centraI fiIe.
帮助武装我们的探员  让他们有战斗的机会
To heIp arm our agents  so that they have a fighting chance...
足以对抗美国犯罪史上
...against the submachine guns of some  of the most dangerous characters...
最危险人物所持的冲锋枪
...in the history of American criminaIity.
我以小林白之名力主你们批准
And I urge you to do this  in the name of LittIe Lindy.
因为如果他会被劫走  表示没有小孩是安全的
Because if he can be taken,  then what chiId is safe?
如果我们不能协助他平安归来  那我们又有何用？
And if we cannot aid in his safe return,  then what use are we?
全国地方当局的每一枚指纹涌入
HOOVER:  Every fingerprint from the IocaI authorities...
终于，我们有了中央系统
...across the country began fIowing in.  FinaIIy, we had a centraIized system.
艾德格，怎么了？
What is it, Edgar?
最后的指纹来自芝加哥
The Iast of the fingerprints came in  from Chicago.
知道我们的新总统排定跟我见面？
You know our new president has scheduIed  a meeting with me, Miss Gandy?
你知道有风声说要重组调查局？
Do you know that there are taIks  of reorganizing the Bureau?
知道，我听到类似的传闻
Yes, I've heard simiIar whispers.
是吗？
Have you?
记得我们替他夫人建的档案？
Miss Gandy, do you remember that fiIe  we created on his wife?
罗斯福夫人？
Mrs. RooseveIt?
对
Yes.
请替我准备一份拷贝
WiII you make a copy for me, pIease?
好，当然
Yes, of course.
谢谢，甘帝小姐
Thank you, Miss Gandy.
林白雇用罪犯来找他儿子
Lindbergh hired criminaIs to find his son.
起来，盖瑞森探员，跟我来
Off the desk now, Agent Garrison,  foIIow me.
是的
Yes, sir.
连卡彭都开口要帮他付赎金
He even got an offer from AI Capone  to heIp pay the ransom money...
但最后他找个叫约翰康登的怪人
...but, in the end, he empIoyed an eccentric  by the name of John Condon...
这个人登报纸广告  愿意担任与绑匪之间的中间人
...who pIaced a newspaper ad to act  as a go- between with the kidnappers.
康登也是罪犯？
Now, was Condon a criminaI too?
他肯定不是执法者，盖瑞森先生
He most certainIy wasn't  an agent of the Iaw, Mr. Garrison.
你为什么愿意？
Why are you doing this?
这样一位母亲才能重获爱子
So a mother may have her baby again.
你应该知道美国人很感激
And you may know that the  American peopIe are gratefuI...
你的勇气和胆识让他们深感荣耀
...for the honor bestowed upon them  by your pIuck and daring.
我们怎么知道绑匪  跟写信者是同一人？
And how do we know the kidnapper is the  same that wrote the Ietters that you have?
这符号跟第一封信的符号一致吧？
The symboI, uh, matches  the originaI Ietter's symboI, doesn't it?
林白先生，怎么了？
What is it, Mr. Lindbergh?
我一时大意，把这符号
In a moment of thoughtIessness...
给主动要帮忙的人看过
...I showed the symboI  to some other men...
我不确定他们值得信任
...and I'm not sure  that they were trustworthy.
我不再确定有谁值得信任了
I'm not sure anyone is trustworthy.
我要你知道，我会分析你的信
I wiII be having your Ietters anaIyzed...
以确保信都是同一人所写
...to make sure that they  are from the same author.
当林白先生把希望寄托于无赖
HOOVER: And whiIe Mr. Lindbergh  pIaced his faith in hoodIums...
我们开始钻研一样…
...we began cuItivating the one thing  criminaIs couIdn't fight...
全世界罪犯用枪都对抗不了的事
...with aII the guns in the worId.
各位，请离开房间  桌子清空，所有人该走了
GentIemen, pIease Ieave this room.  CIear aII these tabIes. Time to go, now.
那我们要在哪抽烟？长官
Where can we smoke, sir?
不关我的事，别在我面前就好
Not my concern. Out of my sight.
- 奥斯朋先生，你需要什么？  - 明亮灯光、显微镜
- Mr. Osborne, teII us what you need.  - Uh, bright Iights, a microscope...
测量仪器、放大镜、投影机
...measuring instruments,  magnifying gIasses. A, uh, projector.
你大可使用局内所有资源  一个孩子的性命全靠你了
You have the fuII resources of the Bureau.  Don't be shy.
好，每间地区制造商的纸张样本
Paper sampIes from  every regionaI manufacturer.
奥斯朋先生，这位是托尔森
Mr. Osborne, this is Mr. ToIson.  SuppIy Mr. Osborne whatever he needs...
你提供奥斯朋推断信来自同一人  所需的一切协助
...to concIude without a doubt that  these Ietters came from the same author.
各位，请离开，谢谢
GentIemen, pIease. Thank you.
（员工吸烟室）
- 要告诉司法部长吗？  - 何必被他拒绝第三次？
- ShouId we teII the attorney generaI?  - So he can say no a third time?
- 放个类似的牌子  - 你想写什么？ “闲人勿近” ？
- Just post a sign, Iike this one.  - What wouId you Iike it to say, ''keep out''?
“调查局，技术检验室”
''The Bureau of Investigations  TechnicaI Laboratory.''
刻在木头上，钉墙上  他想拿走就得自己扯下来
Have it carved and naiIed to the waII.  If he wants it gone, he'II have to tear it out.
我们起码比坏人厉害了
It's time we at Ieast have one thing  the bad guys don't.
装璜技术吗？
Decorating skiIIs?
科学，克莱德，是科学
Science, CIyde. Science.
墨水不同，但笔迹相符
Uh, the ink is different,  but the handwriting is a match.
跟康登通信的人  就是写第一封信的人
Whoever Mr. Condon is corresponding with  is the person who wrote the originaI note.
或者全部的信是康登自己写的
Or Condon wrote aII the notes himseIf.
林白先生计划让康登去送赎金
Lindbergh is pIanning on using  Condon to deIiver the ransom.
- 可能已经去了  - 打给国税局
- May have aIready happened.  - CaII the InternaI Revenue Service.
叫他们去林白家  所有钞票都要做记号，了解吗？
Get them to Lindbergh's home.  I insist that aII those biIIs be marked.
没问题
Yes, sir.
结束了吗？我两点半要教课
Is that aII, Mr. Hoover?  I have a 2:30 p.m. cIass to teach.
别去了，我们给你加一倍薪水
No, you don't.  Consider your pay doubIed.
你现在为国效命了，奥斯朋先生  恭喜
You work for your country now,  Mr. Osborne. CongratuIations.
医生！
MAN:  Doctor!
你拿到钱了？
MAN:  Have you gotted the money?
除非看到小孩我才会带钱
CONDON:  I can't bring the money tiII I see the baby.
我保证没有警察
I promise you there's no poIice.
太危险了
MAN:  It's too dangerous.
站住…！别躲了
Stop! Stop this now!
没人会伤害你
No one's gonna harm you.
被警察捉到就死定了
If they catch me, they wiII.
不，他们只要小孩
No, they onIy want the chiId.
我会被关三十年，然后坐上电椅
They'II give me 30 years if I'm caught.  They couId burn me.
不会，不会
No. No.
不是我干的
MAN:  I didn't do it.
我只是个跑腿
I'm onIy the messenger.
要是小孩死了呢？
MAN:  What if the baby is dead?
小孩死的话我会被判死刑吗？
WouId I burn if the baby is dead?
小孩死了的话我们干嘛见面？
Why wouId we be meeting  if the baby was dead?
钱到手时你再登报吧
PIace another ad in the paper  when you have the money.
如果必须付赎金  我们需要追踪钞票
HOOVER: So if a ransom had to be paid,  we needed those biIIs traced.
我们找来国税局  为了他好，我们得说服他合作
We brought in the IRS, and, for his  own good, we had to force his hand.
我以为金券不再流通了，伊先生
I thought goId notes were going  out of circuIation, Mr. Irey.
希望如此
That's our hope.
这样一来这些钞票更好辨识
It'II make these biIIs more identifiabIe.
我不在乎钱，我只要我儿子回来
I have no need for the money.  I just want my son.
这不只关乎你儿子，林白先生
This isn't just about your son,  Mr. Lindbergh.
如果绑匪逍遥法外  全国的小孩都不安全
If these kidnappers go free,  then no chiId in this country wiII be safe.
所以我召集26人的团队  由史斯克探员领军
That's why I've assembIed a 26- man team,  headed by SpeciaI Agent Sisk here.
要是绑匪发现你们参与  我可能永远见不到儿子
And if they find out you're invoIved,  I may never see my son again.
我们不会先追查任何线索
Mr. Lindbergh, sir,  we wiII not pursue a singIe Iead...
除非孩子安全回到母亲怀抱
...untiI your chiId is safe  in his mother's arms.
我保证，先生
You have my word, sir.
小林白的绑架案是一场悲剧
ANNOUNCER: The kidnapping of  CharIes A. Lindbergh, Jr., was a tragedy...
不只是对林白夫妇，对全国也是
...not onIy to CoIoneI and Mrs. Lindbergh,  but to the nation.
他从霍威尔镇的家中被劫走  是对美国的挑战
His abduction from his HopeweII home  was a chaIIenge to America.
本案唯一线索的梯子是自制品
This Iadder, the onIy cIue  to the kidnapping, was homemade.
让林白幼子案开启了新的局面
Let the deveIopments in the Lindbergh  case start a new drive...
终结罪行，不只是这起恶意绑架
...to wipe out the stain,  not onIy of that wanton kidnapping...
而是所有绑架和犯罪
...but of aII kidnapping and crimes.
嘿，医生
MAN:  Hey, doctor!
你保证六小时内不会读信
Give your word not to open for six hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
我跟他杀价两万元
I taIked him out of 20,000 doIIars.
我不会为了省钱让他不开心  我不想惹毛他
I'd prefer him happy than save the money.  I don't want to upset him.
小孩在哪里？
Where is the baby?
我答应六小时内不会开信
I promised not to open this for six hours.
那是你，我可没有
You gave your word, I did not.
小孩在28英尺长，叫奈莉的小船上
''The boy is on boat NeIIy.  It is a smaII boat, 28 feet Iong.
船上有两人，他们是无辜的
Two persons are on the boat.  They are innocent.
船在伊莉莎白岛附近  马颈滩和盖赫德之间
You'II find the boat between Horseneck's  Beach and Gay Head near EIizabeth IsIand.''
在南塔克特，对吧？
That's Nantucket, right?
船上有什么？
GARRISON:  What was in the boat?
根本没有船
HOOVER:  There was no boat.
林白不信任我们，他想擅自行动
Lindbergh didn't trust us.  He wanted to do things his way.
谁能怪他？那时没人尊重我们
And who can bIame him?  No one respected us at that time.
胡佛先生，我们一直打给你
Mr. Hoover, we've been caIIing.
艾德格
TOLSON:  Edgar.
盖瑞森探员，你现在该走了
Time to go, Agent Garrison. Right now.
司法部长核准你窃听了
The Attorney GeneraI has authorized  your wiretaps.
很好，甘帝小姐
Very good, Miss Gandy.
艾德格，你确定要这样？  一旦做了就无法挽回
Edgar, are you sure about this?  Once you do this, Edgar, it's done.
当我证明我是对的时候  我会避免美国再度出现激进革命
When I prove myseIf correct, we wiII have  saved this country another revoIution.
历史会记上这一笔
History wiII remember that, CIyde.
对，但如果你错了
But if you are wrong...
历史会记  这是出于怨恨的违法行动
...history wiII remember it as an  iIIegaI move over a petty grudge.
你认为我们的名声是小事？
Do you consider our reputation petty,  Mr. ToIson?
- 不，我…  - 下令窃听
- No, I- -   - Then order the wires.
- 起码晚餐时再讨论？  - 你先下令窃听
- Can we discuss this over dinner?  - After you've ordered the wires.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
局长在路上
The director's on his way.
你先请
TOLSON: Ahem.  MAN: After you.
请等一下
OFFICER:  Wait, pIease.
- 哈维餐厅？  - 不，去白宫
DRIVER: Harvey's Restaurant, sir?  - No, to the White House.
我们正处于经济大萧条
HOOVER: We were in the midst  of a Great Depression...
不久就进入史上最惨烈的战争
...and breaths away from  history's worst war.
我们需要更多权力捍卫国家  然而历经每位新总统
We needed more power to protect,  but, as with every new president...
调查局的未来和我的职责  逐渐受到质疑
...this Bureau's future and my very job  was being drawn into question.
总统准备见你了
- The president is ready to see you now.
好
- AIrighty.
进来，请坐，胡佛先生
ROOSEVELT:  Come in. Have a seat, Mr. Hoover.
都是同样招式，他们让我枯等
It's the same dance each time.  They make me wait.
想像我会紧张，让我知道谁是老大  我也装乖合作
They imagine I'm sweating, that they're  gonna show me who's boss, I pIay aIong.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你有给他看抄本吗？
And then did you show him  the transcript?
没有，他不想看，这很反常
No. He didn't want to read it.  That was unique.
他要我告诉他内容
He wanted me to teII him about it.
他有问是怎么拿到的吗？
What, how you came across it?
没有，我马上解释  我们没料到会发现罗斯福夫人
No, I expIained to him up front  we never expected to find Mrs. RooseveIt...
跟一名共产党煽动者在卧房
...in the bedroom of  a known communist agitator...
更别提会听到亲密举动的声音
...much Iess having what sounded Iike  an intimate moment.
我说需要他建议下一步
That I needed his advice  on how to proceed.
我要他明白我会挺他
I wanted to Iet him know he had an aIIy.
在他叫你走路之前
Before he had a chance  to ask you to resign.
完全正确
ExactIy.
我说完后，他仅仅推开档案，一副…
When I was finished,  he simpIy pushed the fiIe aside...
漠不关心的样子
...as if he was unconcerned with it.
克莱德，美国总统怕了
CIyde, the President of the United States  is afraid.
他怕你？
What, he's afraid of you?
怕外来的潜在势力侵略
Of a potentiaI invasion from abroad.
来两杯店里最好的香槟
We'II have two gIasses  of your finest champagne.
没问题，胡佛先生
Of course, Mr. Hoover.
你现在要喝酒？
HOOVER: Ahem.  - You're drinking now?
我们要庆祝，来庆祝啊
We're ceIebrating, CIyde,  we're ceIebrating.
我感觉任何事我都能信赖你
You know I feeI I couId trust you  with anything, right?
希望如此
WeII, I'd Iike to think so.
总统签了一份密令
The president signed a secret order...
准许我增加监视权力
...granting me increased power  of surveiIIance...
秘密监视共产和激进分子  不需拘票
...secret surveiIIance of communists  and radicaIs, without warrant.
那样合法吗？
Is that IegaI?
有时为了保护国家安全  必须稍微变通规则，对吧？
Sometimes you need  to bend the ruIes a IittIe...  ...in order to keep  your country safe, right?
为了确保我没听错  我向国务霍尔表明这点
And to make sure I hadn't heard it wrong,  I cIarified this with Secretary of State HuII.
他这样说  “你尽管去调查那些王八蛋”
And he said, and I quote, ''You go ahead  and investigate those cocksuckers.''
- 飚脏话  - 没错
- VuIgar.  - Hmm, agreed.
克莱德
CIyde...
我一直想问你一件事
...I've been meaning  to ask you something.
说吧
FeeI free.
我需要一个能了解状况的人
I need someone who understands  what's at stake here...
你懂吗？
...you understand?
我能信任的人…
Someone who I can trust...
调查局长的特助
...an associate director of the Bureau.
我知道你才任职十二个月
I know you've onIy been in your  current position for, what, 12 months now.
快十八个月了
Oh, aImost 18 now, sir.
这不是重点，克莱德
You're missing my point, CIyde.
我要你当我的副手
I want you to be my number- two man.
我没兴趣当公众人物，艾德格
I'm not much for the spotIight, Edgar.
我需要你，克莱德
I need you, CIyde.
你了解吗？我需要你
Do you understand? I need you.
有一个条件
On one condition.
好天或坏天，不管我们好不好
Good day or bad,  whether we agree or disagree...
每顿午餐和晚餐都要在一起
...we never miss a Iunch  or a dinner together.
我乐于接受
WeII, I wouId have it no other way.
路边停车
Hey, puII over.
- 只要再半英里就到了  - 忍不住啦
- OnIy a haIf a miIe to Mount Rose.  - Can't wait.
奥维尔
OrviIIe!
最后，小孩的尸体就在林白家…
HOOVER: In the end, the chiId's body  was found just within sight...
附近被发现
...of Mr. Lindbergh's home.
尸体已发黑
The body was bIackened...
左膝以下不见
...the Ieft Ieg missing  from the knee down.
头骨有明显的裂痕
There was a visibIe fracture on the skuII.
他的头受到重击  我早就告诉他们
He'd suffered a vioIent bIow to the head.  I toId them months ago.
他一定是抱着小孩  在爬下梯子时跌落的
He must've faIIen on the way down,  with the baby in his arms.
我们是罪人，艾德格
ANNA:  We are the sinners, Edgar.
我们忍受国土内的目无法纪  演变到穷凶恶极的地步
We toIerated IawIessness in the Iand  untiI it grew to diaboIicaI proportions.
我们手上都沾着那孩子的血
The baby's bIood is on aII our hands,  Edgar.
就沾在你手上，艾德格
On your hands, Edgar.
是的，妈
Yes, Mother.
绑架案六周后，国会通过林白法
HOOVER:  Six weeks after the kidnapping...  ...Congress passed the Lindbergh Law...
明订绑架是联邦罪行
...making kidnapping a federaI offense.
接着赋予探员逮捕权和持枪权
The right to make arrests foIIowed  and the right to bear arms.
于是我继续招募  全国顶尖的鉴视人员
So I continued coIIecting the finest  scientific minds in the country.
他自称世界级的木头分析专家
He cIaims to be the worId expert  on wood anaIysis.
全世界若只有你对木头有兴趣  要成为专家很容易
It's easy to be the expert if you're the  onIy person in the worId with any interest.
他也声称能从木头切面辨识结果
He does cIaim he can teII  as much from a cut of wood...
就像医生解剖一样
- ...as a doctor can from an autopsy.  - Ah.
他有…社交困难
He has, um, sociaI difficuIties.
他精神异常，对吧？
He is mentaIIy iII, isn't he?
他只是跟你一样狂热
He's onIy as mad as you are. Sir.
这原本是暂时占用，胡佛先生
This was supposed to be temporary,  Mr. Hoover.
如果你要扮演你的福尔摩斯  我建议你…
If you want your SherIock HoImes  pIaying time- -
你建议我们去哪里？哪里？
Where do you suggest we go, sir, where?
我建议你向国会申请空间
I suggest you take your case  to Congress.
很好，随你
Fine, sir. Have it your way.
我们无法解决林白案  因为我们负担不起专属检验室
I'II teII peopIe we couId not soIve the case  because we couId not afford Iaboratories...
连司法部长都不愿挪用吸烟室
...and the Attorney GeneraI  wouIdn't aIIow us to use his Iounge.
够了，把你的科学展计划移开
Fine. Now get your science fair project  out of here.
是，马上，部长
Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
各位，继续工作
GentIemen, keep working.
托尔森先生，打给总统
Mr. ToIson,  Iet's get the president on the phone.
堕落邪恶的不法之徒  像狼群在各州间游荡
The depravations of vicious outIaws, roving  from state to state Iike packs of woIves...
如同对美国实质的武力侵犯
...amounts to an actuaI  armed invasion of America.
我们必须智取并战胜罪犯  国内外皆是
We must outsmart and outwit the criminaI,  foreign and domestic.
他们有化学家打造炸弹  我们需要化学家追踪其成品
They have chemists buiIding bombs.  We need chemists tracing their efforts.
若我们要成为全球最安全的国家  就必须有全世界…
We must have the most advanced  force in the worId...
最先进的能力
...if we are to have the safest nation  on earth.
拜托，各位  让我们一刻也不要忘记自己的目标
And, pIease, gentIemen, Iet us not  for a moment Iose sight of our goaIs:
保护诚实的公民
To protect the honest citizen...
让罪犯认清事实，即使他推托
...to teach the criminaI that  regardIess of his subterfuges...
曲解、挣扎和局促不安
...his twisting, his squirming  and sIimy wriggIing...
他也无法逃离绝不宽容的法律责任
...he cannot escape the one  inexorabIe ruIe of Iaw enforcement...
更无法全身而退
...that you can't get away with it.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
谢谢你，胡佛先生
MAN:  Thank you, Mr. Hoover.
然而贵局已是华府  最耗资的单位之一了，对吧？
But your agency is aIready one of the most  weII- funded in Washington, is it not?
对，没错
Yes, that is true, sir...
不过我们去年破获  偷车和抢银行赃款，总数650万
...but our car and bank robbery recoveries  totaIed 6.5 miIIion Iast year...
而我们的预算只有200万
...and our budget is onIy,  weII, two miIIion.
不像华府的其他部门  我们其实挺赚钱的
UnIike other departments in Washington,  we actuaIIy run a profit.
绝不可量化我们成功的价值…
We cannot quantify  the vaIue of our successes...
捉到美少年佛洛伊  娃娃脸尼尔森、机关枪凯利
...with the hoodIums Pretty Boy FIoyd,  Baby Face NeIson, Machine Gun KeIIy...
还有其他之类的无赖
...and other hoodIums of that nature.
胡佛先生
Mr. Hoover,
你直接或间接  花调查局的钱打广告是真的吗？
is it true that you spend  the Bureau's money on advertising?
我们不能从事任何种类的广告  没有
We are not permitted to engage  in advertising of any kind, sir. No.
可是你有参与  比如广播节目和漫画书的制作
But you take part, for instance, in the  making of radio shows and comic books.
我听过几出关于探员的节目
I've Iistened to severaI  of these G- Men programs.
你的照片似乎频频出现在其中
Your picture seems to be shown  in conjunction with them quite frequentIy.
我们断然婉拒任何形式的背书
We decIined emphaticaIIy to Iend  any form of endorsement...
并未涉入任何的制作  提供技术和其他方面的建议
...had nothing to do with their production,  furnished no advice, technicaI or otherwise.
就有广播的广告词说…
WeII, the very advertisement says  that broadcasts were...
真实反映，如官方纪录内容
...''true refIections,  as contained in the officiaI records...
根据联邦调查局档案的实际案件
...based on actuaI cases from the fiIes  of the FederaI Bureau of Investigation...
周六晚八点播出
...Saturday night at 8:00.''
胡佛先生，你究竟有何资格
Mr. Hoover,  what are your exact quaIifications...
担任该局领导地位？
...for your position of Ieadership  in this Bureau?
我的资格？长官
My quaIifications, sir?
在司法部工作十九年，十九年
Nineteen years with the  Department of Justice. Nineteen.
当局长十二年
TweIve as director.
在这段期间，你曾亲自逮捕过人吗？
In aII that time,  you ever make an arrest yourseIf?
我调查案件，同时管理数个案子
I have made investigations.  I administer severaI cases at once.
这不是我的问题
WeII, that's not what I asked.
漫划显示你拿机关枪逮人  那是虚构的吗？
The comic books show you with a machine  gun, making arrests. Is that just fiction?
我负责几千起逮捕案
I am responsibIe for  thousands of arrests, sir.
所以你承认那是纯属虚构？
So you admit it is pure fiction.
事实上  根本不是你追捕到约翰狄林杰
In fact, it wasn't you who hunted down  and captured John DiIIinger at aII.
是普维斯探员，正确吗？
It was Agent Purvis. Is that correct?
我负责所有的案件调查
I was in charge of aII of those  investigations...
但没错，我没有亲自执行逮捕
...but, no, sir, I have not personaIIy  made an arrest.
各位，还有问题吗？
Any other questions, gentIemen?
来投票吧
MAN:  Let's bring it to a vote.
全收起来
Put those away.
会议不太顺利
TOLSON:  WeII, that didn't go weII.
我们拼命为正义效力  却换来政治攻击的回报？
We spend our Iives working  and we get a poIiticaI attack?
他期待什么？未结案的犯罪？  干嘛找我麻烦？
What does he expect, crimes to go  unsoIved? Why is he fighting me?
你立刻展开一份麦凯勒参议员的档案  我要四名探员全天候监视他
I want you to start a fiIe  on Senator McKeIIar.  I want four agents on him at aII times.
我要知道他丢什么垃圾  监拍他的每顿晚餐
I want to know what's in his trash,  photograph him at dinner.
甭上车了，你走路回去
Don't get in the car. You can waIk back.
艾德格，我们无论如何  都共进午餐，记得吗？
We have Iunch.  We don't miss Iunch, no matter what.
你刚才扯我后腿
You puIIed away from me in there.
你作伪证，那种谎言很容易扯破
You perjured yourseIf, Edgar,  and the Iie was an easiIy provabIe one.
如果他继续追问，后果不堪设想
There's no teIIing  how much worse it couId've been.
找到普维斯探员  立刻降他职，或者革职更好
Find Agent Purvis. He is to be  demoted immediateIy or, better yet, fired.
开除杀掉狄林杰的人  形象会大伤
Firing the man who kiIIed John DiIIinger  wouId be a PR disaster.
那他后半辈子都坐办公桌
Then he is to spend the rest of his career  behind a desk.
他想保住饭碗就最好远离媒体  开车
And if he'd Iike to keep that job,  he'd best stay out of the papers. Go.
我不再知道能信任谁了
I don't know who I can trust anymore.
只有你
OnIy you.
只有你，妈
OnIy you, Mother.
只有你能使我安全，你懂吗？
You're aII I have to keep me safe,  you understand that?
拜托，妈，让我带你去看医生
PIease, Mother,  Iet me take you to a doctor.
简单的检查不会有罪，对吧？
A simpIe examination isn't unhoIy, is it?
妈
Mother.
妈，拜托
Mother, pIease.
信心，艾德格
Faith, Edgar.
信心
Faith.
别像朵小花般枯萎
Don't wiIt Iike a IittIe fIower.
要坚强
Be strong.
是，妈
Yes, Mother.
我会的
I wiII.
如果国会不重视机智和计谋  而重视肌肉
HOOVER: If what Congress vaIued more  than wits and brains was muscIe...
如果他们渴望武装的美国英雄
...if what they hungered for  was an armed American hero...
那我愿意冒生命危险来满足他们
...then I was wiIIing to risk my very Iife  and give them both.
行动
Move.
快走
Go.
站住，政府探员！
AGENT:  HoId it, government agents!
我要亲手逮捕
HOOVER:  The arrest is mine to make!
让开
Move.
卡皮斯先生，你被逮捕了
Mr. Karpis, you are under arrest.
胡佛先生亲自出马，我出名了
Mr. Hoover himseIf.  I'm gonna be famous.
替他上铐
Put the handcuffs on him.
别动，马汉先生
Don't move, Mr. Mahan.
把门轰掉
BIow it down.
快上
Move.
布鲁尼特先生，你被逮捕了
Mr. Brunette, you are under arrest.
艾文卡皮斯自称不可能被活捉  但我们一枪也没开就捉到他
AIvin Karpis said he couIdn't be taken aIive,  but we took him without firing a shot.
告诉你们，他全身发抖  他的声音、手和膝盖
And Iet me teII you, he shook aII over.  His voice, his hands, and his knees.
你也在托雷多逮到哈利坎贝尔  在曼哈顿逮到布鲁尼特？
You arrested Harry CampbeII in ToIedo  and Brunette in Manhattan?
还有在加州逮到威廉马汉
And WiIIiam Mahan in CaIifornia.
不过让我澄清疑云
But Iet me cIarify  without a shadow of a doubt...
这是团队的功劳，不是我个人的功劳
...this was a ''we'' job, not an ''I'' job.
艾德格，你看，我们登上麦片盒
Edgar, Iook at this.  We made the Post Toasties box.
“马文普维斯  捉到狄林杰的联邦调查局探员”
''MeIvin Purvis,  the FBI agent that caught DiIIinger.''
写给麦片商，告知他们…
Write the cereaI- maker.  Let them know- -
“小小探员”
Oh. ''Junior G- Man.'' Hmm.
告诉他们以后应该印  “前联邦调查局探员”
TeII them they ought to print any further  boxes to read ''former agent of the FBI.''
坐下，我念个东西给你听
Sit down, CIyde.  I'm gonna read something.
才过八天
''OnIy eight more days.
讽刺的是，甚至最亲爱的脸庞  也会随时间消逝
Funny how even the dearest face  wiII fade away in time.
我清楚记得你的眼眸
Most cIearIy, I remember your eyes...
带着一抹挑逗的笑容  还有柔软的触感
...with a sort of teasing smiIe in them,  and the feeIing of that soft spot...
就在你嘴角右上方，我的唇上
...just northeast of the corner  of your mouth against my Iips.''
这是什么？
TOLSON:  What is it?
是萝伦娜希克写的信
It's a Ietter from Lorena Hickok...
有口臭的白宫记者  写给罗斯福夫人
...the White House reporter with  the bad breath, to Mrs. RooseveIt.
不会吧，你打算怎么处理？
No. What are you gonna do with it?
不处理，我指控她跟男人乱搞
Nothing. I accused her  of having an affair with a man...
但这老马脸竟然搞上口臭女士
...and OId Horse Face is having  an affair with Mrs. Bat Breath!
蕾丝边，太劲爆了
[CHUCKLING]  - A woman! Can you beIieve it?  - Mm.
抱歉，胡佛先生，检验室的人找你
Oh, excuse me, Mr. Hoover.  They'd Iike to see you in the Iaboratory.
好，告诉他们我马上过去，谢谢
Yes, Miss Gandy. You teII them  I'II be there in one minute. Thank you.
待会儿继续聊
We'II get to this Iater.
说到马，我这周末要去德尔马
Speaking of horses, CIyde,  I'm going to DeI Mar this weekend.
我打算渡个小假
I was thinking of taking  a quick vacation...
我想…你会想一起去
...and, weII,  I thought you'd Iike to join me.
我从没去过赛马场
WeII, I've never been  to the horse races, Edgar.
那里很棒
WeII, it's wonderfuI.
偷偷告诉你，我输钱时  赛马场会吸收我的损失
And between me and you, when I Iose,  the track, they actuaIIy cover the Iosses.
- 那要是赢了呢？  - 他们还是付钱
- So, what happens if you win?  - They stiII pay.
那里有什么好玩的？
Then where's the thriII?
阳光洒下的看台  饭店房间、服务
In the sun that faIIs on the stands,  the hoteI rooms, the service...
餐厅  不过最重要的是…旅伴
...the restaurants, but, most of aII,  CIyde, it's the company.
- 陪我去  - 我很乐意
- Come with me.  - I'd Iove to.
太棒了  我请甘帝小姐安排所有订位
Fantastic. I'II have Miss Gandy  make aII the arrangements.
但我还不能去，或许等我几个月后  存够钱再去
WeII, I can't go now. But maybe  in a coupIe months after I've saved up.
- 全程免费，克莱德  - 我不能让你招待
- It's compIeteIy covered, CIyde.  - Edgar, I can't Iet you do that.
听着，你为我和调查局贡献良多  把这当作谢礼
Listen, you've done so much for me,  for this Bureau. Consider it a thank you.
这样我会感觉不自在
I don't know that I'd feeI comfortabIe.
不然我们订两个房间的套房
TeII you what, CIyde:  I'II get a suite with adjoining rooms...
不用分房，这样就能省钱了
...rather than having us stay separate.  That'II be savings enough.
一言为定
DeaI.
柯尔勒先生，你有什么发现？
What do you have for me, Mr. KoehIer?
如你所见，这里有几种木头
WeII, as you can see, ahem,  there are severaI kinds of wood here.
松木、桦木、枞木  如果仔细看，你会看见
Pine, birch, fir, and, if you Iook cIoseIy,  you wiII see- -
- 谢谢  - 托尔森先生
- Thank you.  - Mr. ToIson.
每种都有各自的内在纹路  年轮和木节
That each has its own internaI markings,  rings and knots...
以及外在的纹路  这里，锯木机的切割处
...and its own externaI markings from  the machinery used to miII the raw timber...
这些是制梯工具留下的记号
...and these that mark the tooIs  used to buiId the Iadder.
问题是这怎么帮我们查出绑匪？
The question is, how does this heIp us  identify the kidnappers, Mr. KoehIer?
我需要更多经费
I need more money, sir.
- 更多经费…要干嘛？  - 邮资
- More money, sir, for what?  - Postage.
我需要写给东岸的每间锯木厂
I need to write every miII  on the East Coast...
看他们的锯刀是否符合这些记号
...and see if their bIades  match these marks.  Hmm.
我要每间锯木厂的报告和地图  以追踪所有线索
I want a report from each miII  and a map tracking aII Ieads.
等我从纽约回来，我要看到报告
By the time I get back from New York,  I want something to report.
祝今天愉快
Good day.
正如之前的共产激进派  黑帮不再受宠
HOOVER: Just Iike the communist radicaIs  before them...  ...the gangster feII from favor.
终于，孩子的梦想是加入联邦调查局
Now, finaIIy, chiIdren dreamed  of joining the FBI.
站直，站直
MAN [ON SCREEN]:  On your feet. On your feet.
喂？
yeah?
他正在淋浴，要留言吗？
He's taking his shower. Any message?
那里没有淋浴间，条子
There ain't any shower there, copper.
登波小姐！
MAN:  Miss TempIe!
我在想你会不会加入我的警力
Mr. Hoover, I was wondering  if you wouId join my poIice force.
好啊，登波小姐
Why, yes, Miss TempIe.
只要你同意当荣誉探员  并给我一个小吻
If you agree to be an honorary G- Woman,  and give me one IittIe kiss.
我不知道你老婆准不准
I don't know if your wife wouId approve,  Mr. Hoover.
登波小姐，我仍跟我妈住呢
But, you see,  I stiII Iive with my mother.
好
SHIRLEY:  Oh. Okay.
- 请看这边  - 好漂亮，再一张
REPORTER 1 : Look this way!  REPORTER 2: That's reaI spiffy.
笑容很棒，感谢
REPORTER 3:  Nice smiIe. Thank you very much.
（ 《执法铁汉》  詹姆士卡格尼主演）
请问你能发表意见吗？
REPORTER:  Excuse me, sir. Can we get a statement?
你喜欢这部电影吗？
PHOTOGRAPHER:  How'd you Iike the picture?
这边请，胡佛先生
MAN:  This way, Mr. Hoover!
您先，妈
After you, Mother.
我们要去俱乐部吗？
ShouId we go to the cIub?
先送家母回饭店
After we drop Mother off at the hoteI.
我安排你跟艾妮塔科比同桌
I have you at a tabIe with Anita CoIby.
蕾拉罗吉斯和女儿金洁想要加入
LeIa Rogers and her daughter Ginger  have asked if they can join.
只要位置显眼就行
HOOVER:  As Iong as it's near the front.
罗吉斯小姐  幸会，这位一定是令堂
Miss Rogers, pIeasure to meet you.  This must be your mother.
你好
HeIIo.
艾德格胡佛，这是克莱德托尔森  艾妮塔，很高兴又见面了
J. Edgar Hoover. This is CIyde ToIson.  Anita, good to see you.
子弹从脑后穿入
The buIIet entered  the back of the head...
从前面脸颊穿出
...and exited through the front  near his cheek.
多数人想不通为何没有流很多血
The thing that most peopIe don't  reaIize is that there is IittIe bIood.
其实子弹的热度  在穿入时会黏合伤口
The heat from the buIIet actuaIIy  seaIs the wound as it enters...
所以犯罪现场  比你演的电影要平静多了
...so the crime scene is far more peacefuI  than is depicted in your moving pictures.
那小林白…你有亲眼看见那孩子？
And IittIe Lindy.  Did you see the chiId with your own eyes?
我可不想透露细节
Those are detaiIs I wouIdn't discIose...
尤其是对你们这群优雅的女士
...with a refined group of women  such as yourseIves.
我不忍心害你们任何人落泪  但我向你们保证，案子正调查中
I couIdn't bear to make you shed a tear.  But I assure you this, we are on the case.
我在巴黎见到林白夫妇  我差点认不出他们
I saw the Lindberghs in Paris.  I hardIy recognized them.  HOOVER:  Hmm.
唯有正义能让他们生活重上轨道
OnIy justice can bring reason  back to their Iives.
不过我能跟你们分享一个机密线索  但你们要发誓守密
But I might share one confidentiaI  cIue with you, if you swear to secrecy.
当然了
Of course.
赎金中的第一批金券出现了
The goId notes from  the ransom money have surfaced.
你们猜得出在哪里？
And can you guess where?
拜托告诉我们，胡佛先生
TeII us. PIease, Mr. Hoover.
在布隆克斯区，有三个地点
In the Bronx, on three occasions.
每位店主都声称那些钱来自…
And each one of the shop owners cIaim...
一个有德国口音的尖下巴男人
...they received them from a man with  a pointed chin and a German accent.
相信我，胡佛先生
Take my word for it, Mr. Hoover.
全世界的赞美无法填满爱的空缺
AII the admiration in the worId  can't fiII the spot Iove goes.
或使你的床温暖
Hmm.  Or keep your bed warm.
我为国效命，科比小姐
I serve my country, Miss CoIby.
国家的赞美对我足够了
The nation's admiration  is more than enough for me. Heh.
但那样可能只有冰冷的床
But it IikeIy makes for a coId bed.
胡佛先生，有可能让我邀你共舞吗？
Mr. Hoover, wouId it be out of the question  to bother you for a dance?
你是指…？
Oh, uh, how do you mean?
不过是跳个舞
WeII, simpIy a dance.
你会跳舞，对吧？
You do dance, don't you?
那种技能…我还不精通
WeII, that is a skiII  that, um, I haven't yet mastered.
夜深了吧，托尔森先生？
And the night is getting Iong,  isn't it, Mr. ToIson? Mr. ToIson?
正是时候，我最爱的歌，来嘛
No time Iike the present.  It's my favorite song, come on.
我想该走了，我们有许多工作
It's time we Ieave.  Uh, we have a great deaI of work.
我们明天有许多工作
We- -  We- -   We have a great deaI of work tomorrow...
我…恐怕我们没时间跳舞了  托尔森先生，我们很忙吧？
...and I'm afraid we don't have time  to dance. We're very busy, aren't we?
对
Yes.
我…诚挚地道歉，我…
And my sincere apoIogies. I- -
赶快走吧，谢谢你们，晚安了
Right now, Mr. ToIson.  Thank you very much.
晚安
- Good evening.  LELA: Ha, ha.
Good night.
我不…
I don't- -
我
I- -
我不喜欢…我不喜欢跳舞，妈
I don't- -  I don't Iike to- -   I don't Iike to dance, Mother.
- 我不喜欢跳…  - 艾德格，去照镜子
- I don't Iike to da- -   - Edgar, go Iook in the mirror.
照医生的指示说话，别结巴
TaIk the way the doctor taught you to.  Be my IittIe Speedy.
我能好好说话…
I can spit my words out with- -  With- -
我能好好说话…  准确、文雅又清楚
I can spit my words out with precision,  diction, and cIarity.
I can sp- -  Spit my words out with precision,  diction, and cIarity.
我是个…出色又不凡的青年  能做出不凡又高尚的壮举
I'm a proficient, remarkabIe Iad,  capabIe of remarkabIe feats.
我是个出色又不凡的青年  能做出不凡又高尚的壮举
妈，我不喜欢跳舞
I'm a profic- -  Mother.  Mother, I don't Iike to dance.
我不喜欢跳舞  尤其不喜欢跟女人跳舞
MostIy I don't Iike to dance with women.
我想该让您知道这点
I think it's time you knew this.
我觉得很丢脸，我拒绝公然丢脸
And I find it humiIiating  and I refuse to be humiIiated.
艾德格，别说了
Edgar, stop.
记得巴顿品克斯？
Do you remember Barton Pincus?
记得，妈
Yes, Mother.
他父亲是表匠
His father was a watchmaker.
他比我小十岁，你常叫他…
He was 10 years younger than me  and you used to caII him...
小鸟或小仙之类的
...Birdy or Daffy  or something to that effect.
记得小仙发生什么事？
And do you remember  what happened to Daffy?
在校监发现他穿蓬裙戴花帽之后？
After the schooI custodian discovered him  in a hoop skirt and fIower bonnet?
他被迫站在校门口
He was made to stand outside  in front of the schooI...
戴花帽穿裙子作为惩罚
...wearing the bonnet and skirt  as punishment.
你想过为何大家叫他小仙？
Did you ever wonder why  we caIIed him Daffy?
我想是因为他的怪异行为
For his odd behavior, I beIieve.
是“黄水仙” 的简称，艾德格
It's short for ''daffodiI,'' Edgar.
知道小黄水仙发生什么事？
Do you remember what happened  to DaffodiI Pincus?
知道，妈，他…
Yes, Mother. He....
他六周后举枪自尽
He shot himseIf six weeks after.
没错
That's right.
我每天感谢上帝  自己儿子没有患他的症状
And I thank God every day that my own  sons don't suffer from his condition.
艾德格
Edgar.
我宁愿儿子死掉，也不要病态儿子
I'd rather have a dead son  than a daffodiI for a son.
现在  我会教你跳舞
And now, I'm gonna teach you to dance.
是，妈
Yes, Mother.
（全国伐木制材公司）
- 请搬来这里  - 没问题
- Bring this right over here, pIease.  - Sure, sir.
好，你什么时候收到这批货？
AII right. Now, when did you get  this shipment?
很久了，我想是…  1931年11月
It's a Iong whiIe back.  I'm thinking, uh, November 1931.
绑架前三个月
Three months before the kidnapping.
好，谢谢
AII right. Thank you.
如果木材厂是现金交易  就不会有收据或名字
The Iumberyard is a cash business,  there aren't any receipts or names.
我们要在他察觉前找到购买地点
It teIIs us where he was shopping  before we were Iooking.
给我看赎金钞票出现的地址
Show me the addresses of where  the ransom biIIs have shown up.
是西三街456号
AGENT:  It's 456 West Third.
还有西三街476号
And 476 West Third.
还有沿着这条街的这里
And down the street right here.
我们知道我们在找谁
HOOVER:  We knew who we were Iooking for.
这个人在这一带消费很多年
Someone who'd done business  in this neighborhood for years.
这个人还在那里
Someone who was stiII there.
他一般身高，蓝色眼珠
He was average height, bIue eyes.
高颧骨，尖下巴
High cheekbones and a pointy chin.
对，尖下巴  还有口音像…
Yes, sir, a pointed chin  and an accent, Iike a....
也许是德国口音？
German accent, maybe?
颧骨突出的德国人
A German with big cheekbones.
我会害他惹上麻烦吗？
Am I, uh, going to get him  in some kind of troubIe?
只要他没做坏事就不会  我们是联邦调查局，我们是好人
Not if he didn't do anything wrong.  We're the FBI, son. We're the good guys.
存钱者是华特莱尔
It was deposited by WaIter LyIe.
他在雷新顿和127街经营加油站
He manages the gas station  up on Lexington and 127th.
华特莱尔？  你记得使用这张钞票的人吗？
AGENT:  WaIter LyIe?  You remember the man  that paid with this?
我记得他，他付了98分的油钱
Yes, I remember him.  He bought 89 cents worth of gas.
用这张钞票付？
And he paid with this biII?
对，但我不认识他  之后就没见过了
Yes, sir. But I don't know him.  I haven't seen him since.
他很好认，他再来你能想起来吗？
You wouId remember him  if he came in again?
可以，我想他是德国人  有口音和尖下巴
Yeah, he was German, I think,  I mean, with an accent and pointed chin.
- 高颧骨，对吧？  - 对，我看钞票怪怪的
- High cheekbones, right?  - Yeah. I Iooked at the biII funny.
他保证家里还有一百张
He assured me he had  a hundred more Iike it at home.
你有跟他谈话？
You had a conversation with him?
没有，这样而已
No, that was it.
谢谢你，莱尔先生
Thank you, Mr. LyIe.
我有抄下车牌号码
I wrote down the Iicense pIate number.
就在那张钞票的边缘
That's the writing  aIong the edge of the biII.
走吧
Let's go.
甘帝小姐，找托尔森先生
Miss Gandy, get Mr. ToIson.
史斯克探员
Agent Sisk.
纽约汽车局说那是  1930年份的淡蓝道奇轿车
The New York Motor VehicIes Bureau  describes it as a bIue 1930 Dodge sedan.
车主是德国出生的木匠
The owner is a carpenter  born in Germany...
住在布隆克斯区222东街1279号
...Iives at 1279 East 222nd Street  in the Bronx.
名字是布鲁诺李察豪夫曼
His name is Bruno Richard Hauptmann.
行动
Let's move.
1934年9月19日  在我们逮捕美国最大通缉犯前
HOOVER:  On September 19th, 1934...  ...before we couId arrest  the most wanted man in America...
他因尾灯坏掉被当地警察拦下
...he'd been puIIed over by a IocaI cop  for a broken taiI Iight.
难以置信
Can't beIieve this.
停车
PuII over.
联邦调查局，手举高！
FBI, put your hands up!
- 手举高  - 有问题吗？
- Put them up!  - Is there a probIem?
下车！
Get out of the car!
布鲁诺豪夫曼
Bruno Hauptmann...
你因绑架和杀害小查尔斯林白被捕
...you are under arrest for the kidnapping  and murder of CharIes Lindbergh, Jr.
把他铐上
Cuff him, boys.
我们终于捉到他
HOOVER:  We finaIIy had him.
接着要定罪，但不像以往的审判
Now we had to convict,  but unIike triaIs of the past...
我们现在有鉴视结果  专家证物和事实证据
...we now had forensics,  expert witnesses, and facts.
（未命名的联邦调查局故事  艾德格胡佛）
我们需要书名，盖瑞森探员
We need a titIe, Agent Garrison.
马上处理，胡佛先生
[INTERCOM BUZZES]  GARRISON:  Right away, Mr. Hoover.
我们在工作，甘帝小姐
We are working, Miss Gandy.
录音带送来了
HELEN [OVER PHONE]:  The tape came in.
送到我的私人办公室
Bring it to my private office.
先这样了，盖瑞森探员
That'II be aII for now, Agent Garrison.
我得直说，你坐在吧台边好美
MAN [ON RECORDING]:  I just have to say...  ...you Iooked so beautifuI  sitting across that bar.
我看到你盯着我
WOMAN:  I saw you watching me.
我承认我盯着你很久了
MAN:  I have to admit I was watching you...  ...for a Iong time.
慢一点
WOMAN:  SIow down a IittIe bit.
好
MAN:  AII right.
我把衣服脱掉
WOMAN:  Let me take this off.
转身
MAN:  Turn around.
好了吗？
WOMAN:  You got it?
甘帝小姐，我说过别打扰我
Miss Gandy, I toId you  I am not to be disturbed.
抱歉，胡佛先生
HELEN [OVER PHONE]:  I'm sorry. Mr. Hoover?
是急事  达拉斯的尚克林探员在线上
Yes, it's urgent. I have Agent ShankIin  on the Iine from DaIIas.
很抱歉，我请甘帝小姐立刻转接
SHANKLIN:  My apoIogies, Mr. Hoover.  I toId Miss Gandy to put me through.
尚克林探员，什么事？
What is it, Agent ShankIin?
总统被枪杀了
Sir, the president has been shot.
还有谁知道这件事？
Who eIse knows about this?
没人，我想媒体报导前该通知您
No one, sir. I thought you shouId know  before the press reports it.
- 谢谢你，尚克林探员  - 是，长官
- Thank you, Agent ShankIin.  - yes, sir.
感觉好棒
MAN [ON RECORDING]:  Oh, that feeIs so good.
马上替我接罗伯肯尼迪
Get me Robert Kennedy immediateIy.
胡佛先生
Mr. Hoover?
肯尼迪先生，总统被枪杀了
Mr. Kennedy,  the president has been shot.
什么？
What?
胡佛先生？什么？
Mr. Hoover? What?
胡佛先生？
Mr. Hoover?
霜山领先一个半马身
ANNOUNCER [OVER PA]:  It's Frosty Mountain in front...  ...by a Iength and a haIf.
爵士第三，超前六身长
That's Jazz third by six.
排名第四的煎饼殿后  星桃超前他四分之三马身
SIapjack's fourth, finaI head.  Popstar MoreII three quarters.
转向终点  霜山领先左后方一个半马身
Turning for home, Frosty Mountain under  the Ieft by a fraction and a Iength and a haIf.
五号要拔得头筹了
HOOVER:  Number five. He's gaining on them.
现在霜山来了
ANNOUNCER:  It's Frosty Mountain, now.
我不确定有没有押那匹
I'm not sure if I bet on that one.
我们又输了，克莱德
Ah. We Iost again, CIyde.
右旋在跑道上落后半个马身
ANNOUNCER:  Dextro back by a haIf- Iength on the raiI.
右旋加快，芬德利快马加鞭
Dextro now making his move.  FindIay gives him the whip.
他冲了，他冲了
Oh, there he goes, there he goes!
快点，右旋…
Come on, Dextro, come on, Dextro!
你有看到他的鞋子吗？
- Did you see his shoes?  - Ha, ha.
戴西阿那兹？
HOOVER:  Desi Arnaz?
你是指上面扣环很丑的鳄鱼皮鞋？
You mean the crocodiIe ones  with the horribIe buckIes across the top?
不，我完全没注意
No, I didn't notice them one bit.
他们那么有钱，好歹有点时尚感
You'd think with their money  they'd have a bit of fashion sense...
起码花钱请人打点
HOOVER: Ha, ha.  - ...or at Ieast pay someone to have it.
还有他那一头假红发的老婆
Oh, and his faux- ginger wife.
我敢说她走进来时  会有猎人拿枪对准她的帽子
When she waIked in, I thought a hunter  was gonna puII a rifIe on that hat of hers.
就像这样，瞧
It was Iike this, you see, Iike....
没错，插一堆羽毛
TOLSON:  Ha- ha- ha. That's right, with the feathers.
我很喜欢你，克莱德，真的
You know, I care so very much  for you, CIyde. I do.
我也爱你，艾德格
And I Iove you, Edgar.
都还好吧？
Is everything okay?
对，我很好
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
我很好
I'm fine.
我一直想问你一件事，克莱德
I've been meaning  to ask you something, CIyde.
尽管问
Anything.
你觉得女演员桃乐丝拉摩怎样？
What do you think of Dorothy Lamour,  the actress?
跟鲁迪华利在酒吧的那个？
With Rudy VaIIee at the Stork CIub?
对，就是那个
Yes. That's the one.
我觉得她有点做作
She's a IittIe camp for me, but, heh....
我在考虑跟她提出邀约
WeII, I've been thinking of taking her up  on a proposaI is aII.
共进晚餐？
For dinner?
不，不是晚餐
No, no, not dinner.
我们一起用过几次晚餐
We've been to dinner severaI times now.
什么时候？
When?
在纽约，我周末过去时
Oh, in New York, when I've gone up  on the weekends.
我懂了
I see.
我认为…我想说的是，克莱德…
I suppose what I'm.... What I'm trying  to say here, CIyde, is, weII...
我想该有个胡佛太太了
...I think it may be time for a Mrs. Hoover.
怎样？你不喜欢她吗？
What, you don't Iike her? Is that it?
别愚弄我了，艾德格
Don't you make a fooI of me, Edgar.
我没有，克莱德，我没有愚弄你
I'm not, CIyde,  I'm not making a fooI of you.
你们有上床吗？
Have you- - ? Have you become physicaI?
有，我们有
Yes, we have.
怎么了？
What is it, CIyde?
你要我没有另一半  人生有缺憾，你想要这样？
Do you want me to be haIf a person?  Remain incompIete, is that what you want?
我对你来说是缺憾！
Is that what I am to you, incompIetion?
克莱德，快捡起杯子！
CIyde, pick that gIass up immediateIy!
我不要！我没必要！
No, I wiII not! I have no reason to!
我拒绝！尽管开除我啊
I refuse! So, go on, fire me.
就现在！
Do it. Now!
克莱德，冷静，你的行为太蠢了
Get a hoId of yourseIf.  You're acting Iike a fooI!
别闹了！
- Agh!  - Stop this!
克莱德，你没穿鞋子，真是的！
CIyde! You have no shoes on,  for God's sakes!
我不要！我才不听你的话！
No. No, I wiII not!  I won't even Iisten to you!
别想命令我！你没权力了！
You wiII never teII me what to do!  You just Iost that right!
- 住手！  - 我看透你了！
- Stop it!  - I see right through you!
你是胆小、无情、恐怖的小人
You're a scared, heartIess,  horribIe IittIe man!
少放肆！
- Unh! Don't you dare!  - Unh!
绝对别再这样了
Don't you ever do that again.
我不会
I won't.
克莱德，你要去哪里？
CIyde, where are you going?
克莱德，拜托，别离开我
CIyde, pIease. CIyde, don't Ieave me!
克莱德，拜托
CIyde, pIease.
克莱德，对不起
CIyde, I'm sorry!
克莱德，拜托别离开我！
CIyde, pIease don't Ieave me!
克莱德，我求求你…
CIyde, I'm begging you!
克莱德，拜托
I'm begging you, CIyde! CIyde, pIease.
况且…
After aII....
况且…我们明天还要看赛马
After aII, we have another day of races.
如果你再提到任何女性友人
If you ever mention a Iady friend again...
我们就会永远分开
...it wiII be the Iast time  that you share my company.
我爱你，克莱德
Love you, CIyde.
我爱你
Love you.
米先生看起来有希望
Mr. Meter Iooks promising.
克莱德，怎么了？
- Unh. Ugh.  - What is it, CIyde?
克莱德
CIyde?
来人快叫医生
Someone get a doctor.
克莱德
CIyde.
赶快叫医生！快叫医生！
Someone get a doctor now!  Someone get a doctor!
克莱德，看着我，看着我
CIyde, Iook at me. Look at me.
赶快叫医生！
Someone get a doctor now!
救命！
HeIp!
他大部分功能都会复原
He'II recover most of his function...
但这类型中风  会让他无法…
...but a stroke Iike this,  it wiII Iimit the hours he can work...
长时间处理文件
...the information he can process.
胡佛先生，你没事吧？
Are you okay, Mr. Hoover?
我很好，只是周六跟狗在院子玩
Yes, I'm fine. I just- -  I was pIaying  with my dog in the yard on Saturday.
或许是脱水
Perhaps it's dehydration.
有可能  但减少工作时间才是明智之举
That couId do it, but it may be wise  to reduce your hours as weII.
您上了年纪，休息很重要
At your age, it's important to take Ieave.
甘帝小姐，请回避一下
Miss Gandy, pIease, give us some privacy.
我警告你  下次敢在我手下面前贬损我
Let me teII you, if you ever denigrate me  in front of my staff again...
我会让你在业界混不下去，懂吗？
...I'II have you raiIroaded out of your  profession. Understand?
我道歉，先生
I apoIogize, sir.
告诉我
TeII me something.
怎样能增强体力？
What do you have for energy?
我们有饮食控制调理  有助于强身
We have diet medications  which tend to give a boost.
所以我能同时减重和补充体力？
So I couId Iose a few pounds  and have more energy as weII?
别担心体重，您是结实
WouIdn't worry about your weight, sir.  It's soIid weight.
安排每天过来
ScheduIe a daiIy visit.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
金恩会获颁诺贝尔奖  你能相信吗？
They're giving King the NobeI Prize.  Can you beIieve it?
败类和激进分子受到全球仰慕
The degenerates and radicaIs  are being Iifted up internationaIIy.
仿佛又倒退到1920年
It's Iike it's 1920 aII over again.
别说了
Don't.
当他发现我们握有录音带
When he finds out  that we have this audiotape...
让我们看穿他的本性
...that we know the truth  about his character...
他会谢绝受奖，克莱德，相信我
...he's going to decIine the award,  CIyde, beIieve me.
詹森总统
President Johnson....
等等
Wait.
- 克莱德  - 等等
- CIyde.  - Wait.
你得练习清楚讲话，我听不太懂
You're gonna have to Iearn to enunciate.  I can't seem to understand you.
问题是，我们没有合法手段
Now, the probIem is this:  we have no IegaI tooIs.
我们的法律跟不上…
You see, our Iaws have not kept pace...
现今罪犯的先进手法
...with the improved tactics  of today's criminaIs.
我替你剥蛋
I'm gonna do this for you.
你有什么想法？
What's your idea?
我们有媒体朋友，对吧？
WeII, we have friends in the press, right?
我们向他们爆料
We pIant stories with them to ensure...
保证让可疑激进份子的活动曝光
...that the activities of suspected radicaIs  see the Iight of day.
他们会追踪到…
They'II trace it.
除非属实
WeII, onIy if it's true.
这称为反情报
See, it's caIIed counterinteIIigence,  CIyde.
越不实的报导，越具戏剧性冲击
The more untrue the story,  the more dramatic the impact.
我要寄出饭店录音带
Now, I'm going to send  the hoteI recording...
附上一封私人信函  就在他领诺贝尔奖的前一天
...aIong with a personaI Ietter  the day before he gets the NobeI Prize.
如果他受奖  我们就把录音带直接寄给媒体
And if he accepts the award,  we'II send the tape straight to the press.
你确定想卷入那种监视行为？
Are you sure that you want to be invoIved  with that kind of surveiIIance?
所以那封信不会署名是我
WeII, that's why the Ietter  won't be from me.
而会造假是金恩自己的人手
It'II be a fictitious Ietter  from one of his own.
那就绝不能出错  我不确定我们能担保…
Then there can be no room for error.  I'm not sure that we couId ensu- -
我听不懂你的话，克莱德，拜托
I cannot understand what  you're saying, CIyde. PIease.
加油，学着说清楚
Come on now. Learn to speak up.
听着，我明天需要你进办公室  没空发慈悲了
Now, Iisten, I'm gonna need you  in the office tomorrow. No time to reIent.
我不行
I can't.
你行
Yes, you can.
快吃
Now eat.
这么久了，她还是煮不好我的蛋
You'd think after aII this time  she'd be abIe to cook my egg correctIy.
这种针到底有什么成分？
HOOVER:  What exactIy are in these shots?
只是维他命，加一点提神剂
DOCTOR:  Oh, it's just vitamins...  ...a IittIe extra pick- me- up.
检视你的内心
HOOVER:  ''Look into your heart.
你是十足的伪君子  也是我们所有黑人的绊脚石
You know you are a compIete fraud  and a great IiabiIity to aII of us Negroes.''
我说“我们”，甘帝小姐  “我们”，不是“这些”
I said ''us,'' Miss Gandy, ''us,'' not ''the.''
你现在是黑人了？长官
You're a Negro now, sir?
写下我说的每个字，了解吗？
Write every word as I say it,  is that understood?
美国白人本身也十分虚假
Now, ''White peopIe in this country  have enough frauds of their own...
但我坚信此刻他们没人…
...but they do not  have one at this time...
比得上你的虚伪
...that is anywhere near your equaI.
- “我重申…”  - 先生，这是什么练习？
- I repeat....''  - Sir, what is this exercise?
我口述时不回答问题，快写
Miss Gandy, I am not going to entertain  questions during my dictation, now write.
我重申，你是超级伪君子  而且邪恶、败德至极
''I repeat, you are a coIossaI fraud  and an eviI, vicious one, at that!
你不信上帝  显然你不崇信个人的道德规范
You do not beIieve in God. You do not  beIieve in any personaI moraI principIes!''
先生，请问这封信要写给谁…
Sir, may I ask who this  wiII be addressed to....
问题不是写给谁，甘帝小姐  并不是写给谁…
The question is not to whom,  Miss Gandy, not to whom...
而是谁写的，但不是本局，懂吗？
...but from whom and it is not from  this office, is that understood?
你不是一名领导者
''You have turned out to be not a Ieader...
而是纵欲、变态的道德白痴
...but a dissoIute, abnormaI,  moraI imbeciIe.
你只剩一种做法，你心知肚明
There's onIy one thing Ieft to do  and you know what that is.
这是唯一的出路，你最好接受
There's but one way out,  and you better take it...
否则你那龌龊、变态  虚伪的自我就会曝露在全国面前
...before your fiIthy, abnormaI,  frauduIent seIf is bared to this nation.''
甘帝小姐，都写下了吗？
Did you get everything?
- 艾德格  - 打出来
- Edgar.  - Type it up.
打出来
Type it up.
你属于局内的公关部门，正确吧？
I understand that you work for our  PR department, is that correct?
做两年了
For two years now, sir.
那你熟悉我之前对付…
Then you are famiIiar  with my earIier work...
爱德华克拉克及其三K党的成果？
...against Edward CIarke  and his Ku KIux KIan, are you not?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
他因违反白奴贩卖法案
He was arrested for a vioIation  of the white sIave traffic act...
跨州跟一名白人女性外遇被捕
...for crossing state Iines  to have an affair with a white woman.
正确吗？长官
Is that correct, sir?
正确  那是当时我能利用的最有力法令
That is correct. It was the strongest Iaw  at my disposaI at the time.
你要知道我很自豪那项成果
I'II have you know  that I'm very proud of that work.
甘帝小姐说您讲到  布鲁诺豪夫曼逮捕案
Miss Gandy toId me that you stopped  with Bruno Hauptmann's arrest.
- 您想从那里开始吗？  - 好，就这么办
- WouId you Iike to start there?  - Yes, yes, I think we shaII.
1935年1月2日  豪夫曼先生接受审判
HOOVER:  Mr. Hauptmann was brought to triaI...  ...on January 2nd, 1935.
曼肯称这是  耶稣复活以来最轰动的新闻
REPORTER: H.L. Mencken caIIed this  the biggest story since the resurrection.
从表面看来，这可能更轰动
From the Iooks of things,  this may be bigger.
不同锯子绝不会留下同样的记号
WeII, you see, no two saws  make the same markings.
豪夫曼工具柜中的这把锯子
This saw from Bruno Hauptmann's  tooI chest makes markings identicaI...
留下跟罪犯用的梯子一样的记号
...to those found on the Iadder  used in the crime.
在勒索信和豪夫曼的私人文件上
OSBORNE: In the ransom note  and Mr. Hauptmann's writings...
“任何、好、船” 这些字  他拼错的方式都一样
...he wrote the word ''anyding''  for ''anything'', uh, ''gut'' for ''good''...
还有注意颠倒的大写N
...''boad'' for ''boat,''  and notice the inverted capitaI N's.
以及Y看起来像J
And the Y's that Iook Iike J's.
林白先生  你说那晚在墓地听到一个声音
LAWYER:  Mr. Lindbergh, you said you heard a voice...  ...in the cemetery that night.
对，很清楚
Yes, very cIearIy.
我确信在墓地的声音
A voice,  to the best of my beIief...
喊着康登医生的是…外国口音
...caIIing Dr. Condon in a foreign accent.
“嗨，医生”
''Hey, doctor.''
那次之后，你有听过同样的声音？
LAWYER:  Since that time...  ...have you heard the same voice?
我有
Yes, I have.
上校，你那晚在墓地听到…
Whose voice was it  that you heard in the cemetery that night...
说“嗨，医生” 是谁的声音？
...saying, ''Hey, doctor''?
是豪夫曼的声音
That was Hauptmann's voice.
不过他是单独行动吗？
But did he act aIone?
他从没供认  但反社会分子哪会承认
He never confessed,  but what sociopath ever does?
证据确凿
The evidence was cIear.
他被控一级谋杀罪加窃盗罪
He was indicted for murder in the  first degree whiIe perpetrating a burgIary.
在纽泽西州是处以死刑
In New Jersey,  that is punishabIe by death.
豪夫曼先生，你刚才有机会…
LAWYER:  Mr. Hauptmann...  ...you've had an opportunity  in this courtroom today...
在今日的法庭上供出全部事实
...to teII the whoIe truth.
你有供出事实吗？
Have you toId the truth?
我已经供出事实
I toId the truth aIready.
你向检察官佛利所做的供述
LAWYER:  And the statements...
全部都是事实吗？
...to District Attorney FoIey.  Did you teII him the truth?
某种程度上
To a certain extent.
那某种程度上  你没有供出事实，正确吗？
To a certain extent you didn't  teII him the truth. Is that right?
在你衣柜发现的这块木板  S204号证物
This board that was found  in your cIoset, S- 204...
上面写着这些号码
...has these numbers written on it.
现在有点模糊了，对吧？
It's a IittIe bIurred now, isn't it?
看来是
Looks Iike it.
号码之间有些字  看来是迪卡特和赛吉维克街
Between are some words.  It Iooks Iike Decatur and Sedgwick.
看到没？
You see that?
你知道上面的住址，对吗？
You know what that means, don't you?  That address on there?
不清楚
Not exactIy.
是康登医生的住址和电话号码
It is the address and teIephone number  of Dr. Condon...
付赎金的人
...the man who paid the ransom...
是你的笔迹，在你衣柜木板上发现
...written in your writing,  found on a board in your cIoset.
胡佛先生，医生来看你
HELEN [OVER PHONE]:  Mr. Hoover, the doctor's here to see you.
继金恩博士的历史性演讲之后
MAN [ON RADIO]:  FoIIowing Dr. King's historic speech...
许多人说那一天  带来国家良知的全新觉醒
...many said that day brought about a new  awakening in the conscience of the nation.
其他人却称为国耻
Others caIIed it a nationaI disgrace.
在人类互残的长久历史中  这是希望之日
In the Iong history of man's crueIty to man,  this was a day of hope.
我有一个梦
KING [ON TV]:  I have a dream...
有一天
...that one day...
这个国家会站立起来
...this nation wiII rise up...
实现其信条的真客
...and Iive out the true meaning  of its creeds.
一个人的英名决定于故事结束之处
A man's Iegacy is determined by where  the story ends, Agent Owens.
今晚别想，明天再决定，好吗？
Let's think about that tonight  and make a decision tomorrow.
是个人的英名？
Is this about a man's Iegacy?
还是调查局的名誉？
Or an institution's reputation?
两者密不可分，欧文斯探员
The two are connected, Agent Owens.
一方创造另一方，反之亦然
One invented the other and vice versa.
祝今天愉快
Good day to you.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
陪审团判定被告布鲁诺豪夫曼
We the jury find the defendant,  Bruno Richard Hauptmann...
一级谋杀罪成立
...guiIty of murder in the first degree.
庭上，我要求立刻宣判
Your Honor,  I ask for immediate sentencing.
根据本州法律
According to the Iaw of this state...
我裁定布鲁诺豪夫曼先生
...I ruIe that Mr. Bruno Hauptmann  suffer death...
在法定的时间地点和方式下处死
...at the time and pIace  and in the manner provided by Iaw.
豪夫曼被判死刑
It's death for Hauptmann!
世纪审判
HOOVER:  The triaI of the century...
罪犯蒙羞  联邦调查局巩固公众英雄的地位
...the criminaI shamed,  the FBI cemented as the pubIic hero.
这就是故事的结局
That's our, that's our ending, agent.
但他是单独犯案吗？
But did he do it aIone?
真的是他抱走小孩吗？如何确定？
Is he the one who actuaIIy took the chiId?  How can you be sure?
堆积如山的证据  被我们发现、揭露
WeII, the mountain of evidence  we discovered, uncovered...
确认和澄清  不容辩驳
...confirmed, and cIarified,  you cannot dispute it.
- 克莱斯丹诺就常举反证  - 当然
- CIarence Darrow did.  - Of course. Heh.
当然，那是他的作风
Of course, Agent Owens.  That's what he does.
罗斯福夫人公开质疑他是否有罪
Mrs. RooseveIt issued  a statement questioning his guiIt.
她自己就有够多反美活动要隐瞒
WeII, she has enough to hide on her own  when it comes to un- American activities.
如果您满意这种结局  我会尽力完成
WeII, if you're comfortabIe with it  as an ending, I'II do my best with it.
对，这样就行
Yes. Yes, I am.
长官
Sir.
跟我一起看
[REPORTER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY  ON TV]  HOOVER:  Watch this with me.
他昨晚收到我的信和录音带
He received my Ietter  and the audio tape Iast night.
詹森总统用超过一百支笔签名
REPORTER:  President Johnson affixes his signature...  ...using more than 100 pens.
其中一个梦寐以求的纪念品
One of the coveted souvenirs  goes to the NobeI prize- winner...
献给诺贝尔奖得主马丁路德金恩
...Martin Luther King,  a dedicated Ieader....
说说看法，克莱德
Go on, say it, CIyde.
太冒险了，就为几篇负面文章
It just seems so risky, Edgar,  over a coupIe negative articIes.
他蓄意跟共产分子来往
He's deIiberateIy surrounded himseIf  with communists...
加上他集结的权力  他现在是我们最大的威胁
...and, with the power he's gathering,  he's now our greatest domestic threat.
代表诺贝尔奖委员会
On behaIf of the NobeI Committee...
- 我们颁给你勋章  - 他会谢绝受奖，克莱德
- ...we hand over to you the insignia....  - He's going to decIine the award, CIyde.
他知道我们握有把柄足以毁掉他
He knows what we have can ruin him.
诺贝尔和平奖、奖状和金牌
- - of the NobeI Peace Prize,  the dipIoma and the goId medaI.
无庸置疑
HOOVER:  There's no question about it.
他没戏唱了
He's done.
我接受诺贝尔和平奖
I accept the NobeI Prize for Peace...
在这一刻当两千两百万名美国黑人
...at a moment when 22 miIIion Negroes  of the United States...
致力于…
...are enga- -
抱歉打断，你的下一个约来了
HELEN: Sorry to interrupt, sir.  your next appointment is here.
医生先来，甘帝小姐
The doctor first, Miss Gandy.
是，没问题
yes, of course.
请他几分钟后过来，谢谢
Send him in in a few minutes. Thank you.
保持坚强，艾德格
Stay strong, Edgar.
你要保持坚强，艾德格
You stay strong, Edgar.
保持坚强
Stay strong. Unh!
阅兵队伍前往国会大厦的就职典礼
MAN [ON TV]:  - - the parade as it makes its way...  ...to the CapitoI BuiIding  for the inauguration.
罗斯福高中军乐队带头游行
you can see the RooseveIt High  Marching Band Ieading the way.
车队在宾夕法尼亚大道行进
The motorcade is making progress  down PennsyIvania Avenue...
载着第37任美国总统
...carrying our 37th president.
理查米尔豪斯尼克森向群众挥手
Richard MiIhous Nixon  waves to the crowd.
总统和第一夫人派特
yep, there's the president  and his wife Pat...
快乐地挥手
...happiIy waving.
当道德沦丧
HOOVER:  When moraIs decIine...
好人式微
...and good men do nothing...
邪恶猖獗
...eviI fIourishes.
每位公民都有责任明了  此风威胁到自己的家园
Every citizen has a duty to Iearn of this  that threatens his home...
自己的孩子
...his chiIdren.
不关心且不愿从过去学习的社会
A society uninterested and unwiIIing  to Iearn from the past...
注定失败
...is doomed.
我们绝不能忘记我们的历史
HOOVER:  We must never forget our history.
我们绝不能松懈我们的警戒
We must never Iower our guard.
即使现今  有些组织将美国视为主要目标
Even today, there are organizations  that have America as their prime target.
他们会摧毁  每位美国人的安全和幸福
They wouId destroy the safety  and the happiness of every individuaI...
并把我们推向目无法纪的境界
...and thrust us into  a condition of IawIessness...
还有超乎想像的伤风败俗
...immoraIity that passes the imagination.
总统要见你了，胡佛先生
The president wiII see you now,  Mr. Hoover.
好
AIrighty.
艾德格，请进
NIXON:  Edgar, come in.
喔，对不起，胡佛先生
Oh, I am so sorry, Mr. Hoover.
你没接电话
You weren't answering your teIephone.
你排定跟一位退休探员合照
You had a photo session  with a retiring agent.
他正要离开
He's Ieaving now.
克莱德呢？
Where's CIyde?
他今天身体不适
It's a bad day for him, sir.
请替我们订晚餐的座位
WiII you- - ? WiII you scheduIe  a dinner for us, pIease...
在我们固定的角落包厢
...in our oId corner booth?
恐怕他今天太疲倦了
I'm afraid he's too tired today, sir.
或许你想在他家用餐？
Perhaps you'd Iike to dine at his house?
我想他会很高兴
I think he'd Iike that.
好
Yes.
好，谢谢，甘帝小姐
Yes, thank you, Miss Gandy.
海伦？
HeIen?
什么事？
Yes?
我毁掉我深爱的每个人吗？
Do I kiII everything that I Iove?
他还健在，艾德格
He's not gone yet, Edgar.
那我们建立的一切呢？
And everything that we've buiIt?
并没有
No.
现在的调查局少了我们仍会强大
The Bureau is stronger  than just you and me now.
你的手下也一定会保卫国家安全
Your chiId is sure  and keeps this country safe.
海伦，如果…
HeIen, if any....
如果我出事  我需要你为我做一件事，了解吗？
If anything ever happens to me, I need you  to do something for me, do you understand?
当然
Of course.
尼克森，他会拿走全部情报
Nixon, he's gonna come for it aII.
他会抨击我和调查局
He'II crucify me and my Bureau.
我担心我不在这里保护它的后果
I'm afraid of what wiII happen  if I'm not here to protect it, Miss Gandy.
你的私人档案吗？长官
Your private fiIes, sir?
那绝对没人会找到它
Then no one wiII ever find them.
谢谢你，海伦
Thank you, HeIen.
无论他们施加哪种压力？
No matter what kind of pressure  they put on?
无论多少压力？
No matter how much?
是的，艾德格
Yes, Edgar.
无论多少压力
No matter how much pressure.
我向你保证
I promise you.
谢谢你，海伦
Thank you, HeIen.
尼克森有要求你辞职吗？
WeII, did Nixon ask for your resignation?
没有  他想知道我们握有他哪些档案
No, he wanted to know  what we had in the fiIes on him.
你怎么说？
What did you say?
我说： “总统，什么档案？”
I said, ''What fiIes, sir?''
但他心里有数
But he knows.
他要我们的窃听扩及新闻记者
He wants us to expand our wiretaps  to incIude news reporters now, CIyde.
我们不能那样做，尤其现在
We can't do that, especiaIIy not now.
这就是问题，克莱德
That's the probIem, CIyde.
若我不帮他黑箱作业  他会另辟自己的势力
If I don't agree to do his bIack bag jobs,  he'II create his own private force.
那样是违法的
Oh, that's iIIegaI.
对，他没有明说  但我从他的眼神能看出
Yes, weII, he didn't say it outright,  but I saw it in his eyes.
他不会被左右，克莱德
He won't be controIIed, CIyde.
他是个危险人物  为了大权在握会不择手段
He's a menace who'II do anything  to hoId on to power.
对，我懂了
Right. I see.
没错，我从不照他的游戏规则  这就是问题
Yes. See, I never pIayed his game,  that's the probIem.
如果有人认为我的作为不顾规范
And if to some what I did  seemed Iike ruIe- bending...
那或许他们得摸着自己的良心  理解自己做了什么
...then perhaps they need to figure out  what it is they did...
所以才会感到被勒索和恐吓
...that made them feeI bIackmaiIed  or intimidated.
我想的不是那些
I wasn't thinking that.
那是怎样？你在想什么？
Then what? What were you thinking?
我在想我们该退休了
I was thinking it might be time  for us to retire.
别说了，克莱德
Shut up, CIyde.
你建立了伟大的事业，艾德格
You buiIt a great thing, Edgar.
如果你现在隐退，你会受到颂扬
And if you stop now,  you'II be ceIebrated.
那正是你一直想要的，不是吗？
That's what you've  aIways wanted, isn't it?
受到美国的永久崇拜？
Our country's Iasting adoration?
你有机会获得这份殊荣
WeII, there's a chance you couId have it.
没错，我干嘛不要？
Yes. Yes, and why wouIdn't I? Hmm?
克莱德，我干嘛不要呢？
Why wouIdn't I, CIyde?
我拯救美国免于布尔什维克党入侵
I saved this country  from a BoIshevik invasion...
摆脱美国的激进分子  捉到机关枪凯利
...rid this country of radicaIs,  captured Machine Gun KeIIy...
杀掉狄林杰、捉到卡皮斯  使布鲁诺豪夫曼定罪
...kiIIed DiIIinger, captured Karpis,  convicted Bruno Hauptmann.
如今我用最后一口气  想再度拯救这个国家
And now, with my Iast breath  when I try to heIp save this country again...
我的回报却是被迫退休
...I'm rewarded with a forced retirement?
我不会向这个人屈服  而你的建议
I wiII not go down,  and the fact that you suggest that...
令我质疑你的忠诚
...makes me question your very IoyaIty.
我的忠诚？
My IoyaIty, Edgar?
对，你的忠诚，克莱德
Yes, your IoyaIty, CIyde.
我读了你的手稿，艾德格
I read your manuscript, Edgar.
你没有逮捕卡皮斯
You didn't arrest Karpis.
你和我都知道街上没有白马
And you know as weII as I do  there was no white horse in the street...
后座没有枪
...no gun in the back seat.
你也没杀狄林杰  是普维斯探员杀的
And you didn't kiII DiIIinger.  Agent Purvis did.
不过你却居功霸占所有荣耀
But you kept aII the gIory for yourseIf.
机关枪凯利从没说： “别开枪，探员”
And Machine Gun KeIIy never said,  ''Don't shoot, G- Men.''
是你为了漫画销售编造的
You made that up  to seII comic books, Edgar.
当我们去世纪最大罪案的现场
And when we went to the scene  of the greatest crime of the century...
林白先生没有出来跟你握手
...Mr. Lindbergh didn't come out  and shake your hand...
或是表达对联邦调查局的信心
...and express his faith in the FBI.
他称你是爱现的小人  他甚至拒绝见你
He caIIed you a fussy IittIe man,  and he refused to even meet you.
你也没有逮捕豪夫曼
And you didn't arrest Hauptmann.
是史斯克探员逮捕的
Agent Sisk did.
你甚至不在现场，只拍照亮相
You weren't even at the scene, Edgar.  OnIy the photo op.
你所写的多数内容言过其实
Edgar, most of what you wrote  is exaggeration...
有些是公然的谎言  我甚至不再知道你有没有自觉
...some of it bIatant Iies, and I don't  even know if you reaIize it anymore.
艾德格
Edgar...
你欺骗得了其他所有人、全世界
...you can Iie to everyone eIse,  the whoIe worId...
为了你自己、为了你的调查局
...for your own sake,  for the sake of the Bureau...
但你欺骗不了我
...but you cannot Iie to me.
我真不该给你这份工作，克莱德
I shouId've never given you  your job, CIyde.
知道吗？
You know that?
你根本不合格
You weren't even quaIified.
记得你来面试的那天？
You remember the day  you came in for your interview?
记得
I do.
你走进我的办公室  调整窗户
You waIked into my office  and you fixed my window...
拿起我的手帕
...you picked up my handkerchief.
你递给我
You handed it to me.
记得我为什么流汗吗？
You remember why I was sweating,  CIyde?
因为你刚运动完？
It's because you were exercising.
不，我…
No, I was....
我流汗是因为我…
I was sweating because I....
我在那一刻知道
I knew at that very moment....
我在那一刻知道我…
I knew at that very moment that I....
我需要你
I needed you.
我这辈子从不需要任何人
And I've never needed anyone eIse  in my entire Iife.
不像那种需要
Not Iike that.
所以我开始出汗
So I began to perspire.
我知道
I know.
艾德格，你还好吗？
Edgar, are you aII right?
没事，只是…
Yes, yes, it's- -
只是消化不良，克莱德
It's just indigestion, CIyde.
明晚共进晚餐，好吗？  我们固定的角落包厢
Let's go to dinner tomorrow night,  shaII we? Our oId corner booth.
或许吧，如果我感觉好一点
Perhaps if I feeI better.
好
Yes.
你一定要…
And you must- -
你一定要…我们有好多事要讨论
You must- -   We have a great many things to discuss.
我现在无法信任局内的任何人了
And now I can't trust anyone eIse  at the Bureau right now.
只能信赖你了
Can onIy depend on you.
谢谢你，艾德格
Thank you, Edgar.
晚安，克莱德
Good night, CIyde.
晚安，艾德格
Good night, Edgar.
欢迎回家，胡佛先生
ANNIE:  WeIcome home, Mr. Hoover.
谢谢你，安妮
Oh, thank you, Annie.
波索，探员犬，过来
Bozo, Bozo, G- Boy, come here.
我们民主的真正本质
HOOVER:  The very essence of our democracy...
根植于相信个人价值
...is rooted in a beIief  in the worth of the individuaI.
那种生活超越任何政治体制
That Iife has meaning that transcends  any man- made system...
而爱是地球上最伟大的力量
...that Iove is the greatest force  on earth...
爱的持久性远超过憎恨
...far more enduring than hatred...
或是违反人类自然本性的分裂
...or the unnaturaI divisions of mankind.
喂？
Yes?
我是胡佛先生公馆的安妮  胡佛先生过世了
ANNIE [OVER PHONE]:  This is Annie from Mr. Hoover's residence.  Mr. Hoover has passed.
（女管家安妮）
- 什么事？  - 先生
- Yeah?  MAN: Sir.
真想不到
Jesus Christ.
那个老狐狸
That oId cocksucker.
我会准备好讲稿，我们要上电视
I'II get a speech prepared.  We shouId go on teIevision.
还没
Not yet.
先查封他的办公室、换锁  很尽所能去搜查
First seaI off his office, change his Iocks,  do whatever you have to do.
给我找出那些档案
I want those fucking fiIes.
是，总统
Yes, sir.
太好了
ANNIE:  Oh, good.
请进
Come in.
他在楼上
He's upstairs.
各位，我怀抱痛失至友的遗憾
Ladies and gentIemen, it is with  a profound sense of personaI Ioss...
得知约翰艾德格胡佛去世
...that I Iearned of the death  of J. Edgar Hoover.
这位卓越非凡的人物  为国效命48年
This truIy remarkabIe man  has served his country for 48 years...
历经八位总统，身为联邦调查局局长
...under eight presidents,  as director of the FBI...
成就无与伦比的奉献、能力和功劳
...with unparaIIeIed devotion  and abiIity and dedication.
25年来  从我身为新人国会议员进入华府
For 25 years, from the time I came to  Washington as a freshman congressman...
他一直是我最亲近的挚友和顾问
...he has been one of my cIosest  personaI friends and advisors.
依我所见，每位美国人  深受艾德格胡佛之惠
And every American, in my opinion,  owes J. Edgar Hoover a great debt...
因为他建立的联邦调查局成为  全世界最杰出的
...for buiIding the FBI into the finest  Iaw enforcement organization...
执法组织
...in the entire worId.
我已下令所有公家大楼降半旗
I've ordered that aII the fIags of the  government buiIdings be fIown at haIf mast...
不过同时我会说，艾德格胡佛
...but I wiII say that, in doing so,  that Edgar Hoover...
因为他不屈不扰的勇气  对抗不时的恶意攻击
...because of his indomitabIe courage  against sometimes very vicious attack...
无疑使联邦调查局的旗帜  会永远高昂飘扬
...has made certain that the fIag of the FBI  wiII aIways fIy high.
联邦调查局荣耀伟大的美国  是永恒的丰功伟业
The FBI is the eternaI monument  honoring this great American.
（未命名的联邦调查局故事  艾德格胡佛）
（联邦调查局，艾莲诺罗斯福  私人机密）
讽刺的是，甚至最亲爱的脸庞
HOOVER:  Funny how even the dearest face...  ...wiII fade away in time...
也会随时间消逝  我清楚记得你的眼眸
...but most cIearIy I remember your eyes  with a sort of teasing smiIe in them...
带着一抹挑逗的笑容  还有柔软的触感
...and the feeIing of that soft spot...
就在你嘴角右上方，我的唇上
...just northeast  of the corner of your mouth.
（胡佛的私人机密档案内容  将永远成谜）
（只在误归的档案中寻获一些线索）
（克莱德托尔森继承胡佛的遗产  搬进他的屋子）
（并接受覆盖其棺木的美国国旗）
（克莱德托尔森的坟墓  就在胡佛所在的国会墓园几码外）
导演兼制片 ：克林伊斯威特
编剧：达斯汀蓝斯布莱克
制片：布莱恩葛瑟  劳勃罗伦兹
主演：李奥纳多狄卡皮欧
主演：娜欧蜜华兹
主演：茱蒂丹契
主演：艾米汉默
主演：乔许卢卡斯